<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post-rsses on Conor&#39;s Bandon Blog</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.com/post/atom/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post-rsses on Conor&#39;s Bandon Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 19:17:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.com/post/atom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>My first ever IMRA/MMRA trail run in Castlefreke - impressive turnout and tons of kids!</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.com/2017/02/05/my-first-ever-imra-mmra-trail-run-in-castlefreke/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 19:17:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.com/2017/02/05/my-first-ever-imra-mmra-trail-run-in-castlefreke/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I only learned of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imra.ie/&#34;&gt;Irish Mountain Running Assocation&lt;/a&gt; (and Munster Mountain Running Association branch) last year. They have &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imra.ie/events/&#34;&gt;an extensive line-up of events&lt;/a&gt; all year from hard-core 127km Ultras to family friendly events like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imra.ie/events/view/id/1477&#34;&gt;today&amp;rsquo;s run&lt;/a&gt; in Castlefreke Woods and Long Strand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/2017-02-05%2010.52.35b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Castlefreke Forest&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And unlike a lot of running related things in recent years, it&amp;rsquo;s an absolute bargain to take part. €10 annual membership and €5 for today&amp;rsquo;s race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had no idea what to expect today. Would it be 10 people or 100? Beginners or Jim Walmsleys? It was a good mixed group of people. The turnout for the junior race was really impressive. I regretted not bringing some of my brood, I think they would have enjoyed it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/2017-02-05%2010.36.07b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Junior Race&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I identified the very serious mountain people by their shoes. Anyone in Salomon or Inov-8 was clearly not messing around. I had my US-trail-style Altra Lone Peaks which were perfect for today&amp;rsquo;s conditions but had very poor downhill grip before Christmas when I tried to do part of St Finbarr&amp;rsquo;s Way from the Gougane Barra side and landed on my arse several times coming back down in boggy muddy wet conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course today had to be changed due to flooding on the path out to Kilkern Lake. It was manky when I did it before Christmas too. This meant that they added an extra nasty road hill but it gave me a chance to go on the newish trail parallel to Long Strand which is lovely, albeit too short.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The view as you come to the top of the hill on the road out of Rathbarry is utter perfection. If I hadn&amp;rsquo;t been so intent on not coming last, I&amp;rsquo;d have stopped for 5 minutes just to soak it in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The run was brilliant. The bit along Long Strand was pure torture, just like the last time I did a run here, so I had to walk most of it. There is no hard packed sand on that beach so you sink in with every footstep. At least now I know I&amp;rsquo;m never doing &lt;a href=&#34;http://marathondessables.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Marathon Des Sables&lt;/a&gt; :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/16422850_1267538586672655_2746855433585271530_o.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Long Strand&#34; /&gt;
(Pic from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/405709882855534/photos/pcb.1267541266672387/1267538586672655/?type=3&amp;amp;theater&#34;&gt;MMRA Facebook Group&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The climb up to the big cross got the heart pumping and the hell-for-leather run down the other side to the end was a blast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t recommend runs like this highly enough. They are cheap, mostly short, friendly, fun and have everyone from mountain goats to blobs like me. Check out that list on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imra.ie/events/&#34;&gt;the events page&lt;/a&gt; and get yourself out there for the next one. In the meantime &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/MMRA-Munster-Mountain-Running-Association-405709882855534/&#34;&gt;the MMRA Facebook Page&lt;/a&gt; has lots of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/permalink.php?story_fbid=1267492480010599&amp;amp;id=405709882855534&#34;&gt;pics from today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go to a parkrun this Saturday in West Cork</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.com/2017/01/26/go-to-a-parkrun-this-saturday-in-west-cork/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 20:43:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.com/2017/01/26/go-to-a-parkrun-this-saturday-in-west-cork/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I talked about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.parkrun.com/&#34;&gt;parkrun&lt;/a&gt; in my monster post last year on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://conoroneill.com/2016/09/21/greenways-byways-hedgerows-tourism-and-the-future-of-irelands-health/&#34;&gt;future of Ireland&amp;rsquo;s health&lt;/a&gt;. It was started in the UK in 2010 and has spread around the world. In &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.parkrun.ie/&#34;&gt;parkrun Ireland&lt;/a&gt; there are over 50 events every week. You may have heard it mentioned on &lt;a href=&#34;https://ot.rte.ie/&#34;&gt;Operation Transformation&lt;/a&gt; too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/parkrun.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Parkrun&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is incredibly simple. Every Saturday at 9.30am, you turn up to your local parkrun and do 5km. You can sprint, run, jog, walk or amble. If you sign up on the web-site, you get a printable barcode so your time can be recorded every week. A few hours after taking part, you&amp;rsquo;ll get all the stats by email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.parkrun.ie/clonakilty/&#34;&gt;Clonakilty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.parkrun.ie/castlehaven/&#34;&gt;Castlehaven&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.parkrun.ie/castledemense/&#34;&gt;Macroom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.parkrun.ie/ballincollig/&#34;&gt;Ballincollig&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.parkrun.ie/bereisland/&#34;&gt;Bere Island&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.parkrun.ie/glengarriff/&#34;&gt;Glengarriff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finally signed up 3 weeks ago and headed down to the Clonakilty Show Grounds - it&amp;rsquo;s behind The Boiler for all you West Cork parents reading this :-) The run is 4 loops of the grounds and the participants included everyone from out-and-out speedsters to people having a gentle walk or pushing a buggy. There is no pressure to &amp;ldquo;perform&amp;rdquo; and you can never come last, as they always have an organiser at the back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The organisers are &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;. Every week it&amp;rsquo;s run by those who volunteer. I&amp;rsquo;ve done three runs now and it&amp;rsquo;s starting to approach the time I volunteer and do my bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clon had 40ish people each of the weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve been there and it&amp;rsquo;s brilliant to see the Operation Transformation walkers out too. It&amp;rsquo;s an extremely welcoming setup where they do a shout-out to all newbies and all the &amp;ldquo;tourists&amp;rdquo; from other parkruns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m interested in doing Ballincollig too but the numbers there are wonderfully nuts (approx 400 people!). We&amp;rsquo;ll delicately skip over the nonsensical situation in Tramore Valley Park that caused this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also really want to try Bere Island. I love the idea of getting on a ferry out to an island to do a run. But it&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a trip down the Beara peninsula to get there for 9.30am. Maybe when the mornings are a bit brighter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone on Twitter recently suggested doing one in Bandon. I think this is a superb idea but with some logistical issues. parkruns are done in open spaces, not on paths or roads. So the options I think we have are (with the associated challenges):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bandon RFC - Everyone would have to be out of there before 10.30 when the crowds really start building for the matches/training. Only a problem in winter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GAA - Not sure when training happens here. It&amp;rsquo;s the most central with lots of parking too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Town Park - Would interfere with Saturday soccer. Also very little parking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bandon Grammar - Not sure if the hockey pitch is suitable. And again, training clashes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Golf Club driving range - It&amp;rsquo;s a bit far out but it&amp;rsquo;s almost exactly 1km around so it would be 5 simple loops and people have been running there for years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One hope for the future is that Castlebernard is mentioned in some &lt;a href=&#34;http://corklocalareaplans.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/Draft-Bandon-Kinsale-MD-LAP.pdf&#34;&gt;very cool plans by Cork CoCo&lt;/a&gt; (note that&amp;rsquo;s a PDF) for Bandon. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if those plans are just ideas or have actually been agreed with the owners. If there was a riverside path out to there with a run around some new tracks, that would fantastic for parkrun and make Bandon a really attractive place to visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any other suggestions for how we could do it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So come on, overcome your self-consciousness and self-confidence issues and give it a go. You don&amp;rsquo;t even need a pair of runners or running gear. Come out for a walk and see what you think. Watch this old fart staggering around out-of-breath trying to break my Personal Best time and maybe you might consider a jog at some point in the future. No one is judging you, they are applauding you for giving it a go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Say hello if I convinced you to try it :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s Dawn Nisbet in the UK who started and never looked back. Her picture has &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.com/news/uk-england-manchester-38731822&#34;&gt;gone viral&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/dawn_nisbet.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Dawn Nisbet&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be remiss of me not to mention &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bandonac.org/wordpress/?page_id=573&#34;&gt;Bandon FIT4LIFE&lt;/a&gt; too. You can contact the Club at 087-4340860. They have 3 different times for different levels of fitness. They also have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/groups/1650142431918861/&#34;&gt;Facebook Page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, please read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.runselfierepeat.com/blog/the-fastest-way-to-get-a-perfect-body&#34;&gt;this brilliant blogpost&lt;/a&gt; by Kelly Roberts. I absolutely love her &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCAMukAUAEGn0Ij1N195BuGw/videos&#34;&gt;BQ or Bust YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt; but this piece on the fastest way to get a perfect body just nails it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acknowledging the achievement of Carol Morgan in The Spine Race</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.com/2017/01/22/acknowledging-the-achievement-of-carol-morgan-in-the-spine-race/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 20:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.com/2017/01/22/acknowledging-the-achievement-of-carol-morgan-in-the-spine-race/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I first learned of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://thespinerace.com/&#34;&gt;Montane Spine Race&lt;/a&gt; last year when there were some mentions online of an Irish guy winning some insanely long race and breaking the record. This turned out to be &lt;a href=&#34;https://eoinkeith.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;Eoin Keith&lt;/a&gt; who is an amazing ultra runner. He had to pull out this year in third position after breaking a rib near the start. He waited 170 miles to do so :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/the-running-blog/picture/2017/jan/20/picture-of-the-day-britains-most-brutal-race/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/5760.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
(Image Source &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/the-running-blog/picture/2017/jan/20/picture-of-the-day-britains-most-brutal-race/&#34;&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt;)
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yup, the Spine Race is 268 miles along the Pennines in the UK. Only the toughest of the tough get to the end. The more I watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/TheSpineRace/&#34;&gt;the coverage&lt;/a&gt; last week, the more my admiration grew. These are a special breed of people who want to push themselves to extremes of physical and mental exhaustion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/854e58_76398849d08f408faec9e5f890cfc31f.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Spine Race Map&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-video&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;WHY???? run 268miles &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MONTANEuk&#34;&gt;@MONTANEuk&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/TheSpineRace&#34;&gt;@TheSpineRace&lt;/a&gt; ????? &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Columbia1938&#34;&gt;@Columbia1938&lt;/a&gt; athlete Eoin Keith sums it up &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/spinerace?src=hash&#34;&gt;#spinerace&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/XXrQOtSuMn&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/XXrQOtSuMn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Trail Running mag (@TrailRunningMag) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/TrailRunningMag/status/821737289474834432&#34;&gt;January 18, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which brings us to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.grough.co.uk/magazine/2017/01/20/carol-morgan-smashes-record-by-43-hours-to-take-womens-title-in-spine-race&#34;&gt;Carol Morgan&lt;/a&gt;. She is an Irish nurse working in Leeds who has already finished world famous ultras like &lt;a href=&#34;http://utmbmontblanc.com/en/&#34;&gt;UTMB&lt;/a&gt;. Carol went out last week and finished as the first woman. This is already an huge achievement for any human. Then you realise she was joint 6th &lt;em&gt;overall&lt;/em&gt;. Then you learn that she beat the previous record by 43 hours! Finally you realise she finished a day ahead of the second placed woman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/spine_race_carol_morgan.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Carol&#39;s Time&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just a spectacular sporting achievement and everyone in the country should be talking about it just as much as any Olympic medallist. But we know they won&amp;rsquo;t because that&amp;rsquo;s not how mainstream media works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.grough.co.uk/magazine/2017/01/20/carol-morgan-smashes-record-by-43-hours-to-take-womens-title-in-spine-race&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/The-Spine-2017-White-Hill-Carol-Morgan-1024x682.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
(Image Source &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.grough.co.uk/magazine/2017/01/20/carol-morgan-smashes-record-by-43-hours-to-take-womens-title-in-spine-race&#34;&gt;The Grough&lt;/a&gt;)
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carol appears to be a very private person who declined to have any video footage taken of her competing in the race. But I just wanted to say that her win last week is genuinely inspirational for me. I&amp;rsquo;ve never run more than 26.2 miles and I&amp;rsquo;ve never run more than 15 miles off road. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I&amp;rsquo;ll ever try to do 268 miles, but if I do, it&amp;rsquo;ll be because of people like Carol and Eoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It strikes me that Irish people are particularly suited to Ultra running due to the fact that we are all stubborn feckers. I think we&amp;rsquo;re going to see a major uptick in this area in Ireland in the next few years. Far beyond Adventure races, Tris and traditional XC. The mix of run-walk that many competitors  do over these very long distances is much more manageable for a wider range of people. And it doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to cost anything beyond some runners, wet gear, a compass and a map (I know I know, there&amp;rsquo;s more to it than that).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now to find my first trail 50k. In the meantime, I might see some of you at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imra.ie/events/&#34;&gt;IMRA&lt;/a&gt; 5 miler &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imra.ie/events/view/id/1477&#34;&gt;in Castlefreke&lt;/a&gt; on February 5th?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FTheSpineRace%2Fvideos%2F1296747880412904%2F&amp;show_text=0&amp;width=560&#34; width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; style=&#34;border:none;overflow:hidden&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowTransparency=&#34;true&#34; allowFullScreen=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing the carnage to the Dublin Marathon 2016</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.com/2016/11/20/bringing-the-carnage-to-the-dublin-city-marathon-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2016 20:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.com/2016/11/20/bringing-the-carnage-to-the-dublin-city-marathon-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Four years ago I ran my first marathon, in Dublin, and it was a disaster. Everything seized up at the top of my right calf around mile 10, followed a few miles later by my left calf. I hobbled the remaining 16 miles in pain. It had never happened before and it hasn&amp;rsquo;t happened since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought that was the end of my marathon &amp;ldquo;career&amp;rdquo; and reverted to Halves and 10k&amp;rsquo;s until last year. I finally got the confidence up again and did both Tralee and London. This year was a bit nuts with Manchester, Lakes of Killarney, Cork and Berlin. But at the back of my mind I wanted to do Dublin again and get revenge for the 2012 horror.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did it go well? Too bloody right it did! Not only did I get revenge, I got PBs for 15k, 10 Miles, 20k, Half Marathon, 30k &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; Marathon. I&amp;rsquo;m bloody chuffed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/Km7o3w2fs5Y&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything went right for me. I ran faster than planned for 10 miles then collapsed in speed as I always do. But a few faster ones in the middle and an very solid finish, despite walking all of Milltown, Clonskeagh and Roebuck, was enough to give me the result I wanted.  Yeah yeah, I run barely above the pace of a walker, but I&amp;rsquo;m happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to thank the following:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All of our family and friends who came out to shout. It&amp;rsquo;s an incredibly powerful motivator to see people you know.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Joey, Johnny, Dee Dee and Tommy Ramone for getting me through the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zGgfHZ02I2k&#34;&gt;last 3 miles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andy from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.headspace.com&#34;&gt;Headspace&lt;/a&gt; whose calming dulcet tones popped into my mind several times during the hard bits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/walmsley172?lang=en&#34;&gt;Jim Walmsley&lt;/a&gt; whose interview on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=t33Zi7Pe-jk&#34;&gt;Ginger Runner Live&lt;/a&gt; kept going around in my head. He said he&amp;rsquo;d bring the carnage to Western States next year. I turned that into a little personal mantra of &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m bringing the carnage&amp;rdquo;. Of course in my case it was carnage on my body :-) But it really worked. Along with 26 miles of me telling myself &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve got this&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Couple of notes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The atmosphere before, during and after is wonderful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The newer route is much better. I didn&amp;rsquo;t mind the Phoenix Park this time at all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drinks stations worked perfectly for me. Faultless.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Like Cork, generic dance music seemed to work better for me than podcasts for the bulk of the race&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whoever told the German runner I met that Dublin is as flat as Berlin is an evil person :-) When I told the poor guy going up Milltown that the two worst hills were still to come, he was very very unhappy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The supporters were fantastic as always. More bands like Berlin and London would be good tho.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had far more chats than usual due to my Berlin Marathon running top. It&amp;rsquo;s a great conversation starter for others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They need to rearrange the bag drop-off. Despite our hotel being 5 mins from the start line, I think we walked 2+ miles going to/from bag-drop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RTE is a laughable embarassment. Did RTE Sport hide under their desks for the day, as we ran past their offices? Rather than live broadcasting the largest single mass participatory sporting event in the country and the fourth largest marathon in Europe? If RTE doesn&amp;rsquo;t think that&amp;rsquo;s public service broadcasting then it should be shutdown and give us all our money back.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Marathon should forget about the RTE dinosaurs and arrange live streaming themselves like UTMB does. Thousands of people watched UTMB this year and that&amp;rsquo;s a tiny niche race compared to Dublin. With the right global promotion, Dublin could be a huge online media event.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are thinking about your first marathon or first Irish marathon, you should seriously consider Dublin. Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s very hilly compared to Berlin, London or Manchester. But it&amp;rsquo;s easier than many and the crowds really are superb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/dublin_marathon_medal.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Medal&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why we need more events like Ginger Runner Virtual Run #GRVR16</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.com/2016/11/20/why-we-need-more-events-like-ginger-runner-virtual-run-grvr16/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2016 20:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.com/2016/11/20/why-we-need-more-events-like-ginger-runner-virtual-run-grvr16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever Googled for video reviews of running shoes, you&amp;rsquo;ve almost definitely landed on a review by &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtube.com/thegingerrunner&#34;&gt;The Ginger Runner&lt;/a&gt;, Ethan Newberry. For a long time, that was all I knew him for and I bought several pairs after confirming that he liked them. Then I discovered &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=t33Zi7Pe-jk&#34;&gt;Ginger Runner Live&lt;/a&gt;, where he does long interviews with ultra runners live on YouTube. These are my goto podcasts whilst running slowly, along with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.badboyrunningpodcast.com/&#34;&gt;Bad Boys Running&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://ultrarunnerpodcast.com/category/podcasts/&#34;&gt;The Ultra Runner Podcast&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/adam-buxton&#34;&gt;Adam Buxton&lt;/a&gt; (who may not be a runner :-) ).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few months back Ethan announced The Ginger Runner Virtual Run. On Nov 19th, all entrants had to run for exactly two hours anywhere in the world and upload their GPS trace to Strava. There was lots of swag and a variety of prizes. I just loved the idea of a virtual community all doing the same thing on the same day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/long_strand_from_top_of_hill.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;long strand from top of hill&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yesterday I headed out with the car thermometer at 0C and drove to the back of Long Strand. I then spent 2 hours running around Castlefreke Woods, Rathbarry, over to Owenahincha and on to Long Strand itself. It start badly with me wading through 6 inches of water on a flooded trail but I soon warmed up. The rain that followed was not welcome but I didn&amp;rsquo;t mind it at all. And you know what? It was bloody great! I moved at an even slower than my usual sloth pace and took videos and &lt;a href=&#34;https://goo.gl/photos/KjVB9ZhdCyh3pFef8&#34;&gt;pictures&lt;/a&gt; and talked to a donkey and said hello to lots of walkers and some other runners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the end I was tired and wet and smiling from ear to ear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then I have been looking through all of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search?f=tweets&amp;amp;vertical=default&amp;amp;q=%23GRVR16%20OR%20%23GRVR&amp;amp;src=typd&#34;&gt;pictures, videos, tweets&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/thegingerrunner/?fref=ts&#34;&gt;Facebook comments&lt;/a&gt; from others who took part. Like many running events, it has every type of runner, from blobs like me to ledgebags like &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MountainOutpost&#34;&gt;Jamil Coury&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/1smkYBZFkWo&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course this is a commercial endeavour for Ethan, but he deserves every penny he makes from it. He puts enormous effort into his running films and all of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gingerrunner.com/&#34;&gt;Ginger Runner media&lt;/a&gt; and it&amp;rsquo;s only fair that those of us who benefit from his work/art should give something back, not just via ad eyeballs and affiliate links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope the success of this encourages people in other fields to do something similar. As I said on Twitter, community is about shared interests, not just physical proximity. For all the brutal flaws of social media, particularly recently, Ethan has shown how it can bring groups of us closer together, even if just for a few damp hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS: I was massively impressed with how quickly the Altra Lone Peak 3.0 drained after I waded through that water. After 5 minutes I&amp;rsquo;d forgotten I&amp;rsquo;d been soaking. There was no squelching and my socks were just a bit damp at the end of the run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS 2: The &lt;a href=&#34;http://conoroneill.com/2016/10/02/timoleague-courtmacsherry-elephone-explorer-pro/&#34;&gt;Elephone Explorer Pro&lt;/a&gt; needs a power bank permanently connected to it if you want it to even be powered up for two hours, let alone recording. As you can see, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty poor quality video but probably good enough for me for the moment. I&amp;rsquo;m mightily tempted by that new Garmin Virb tho.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timoleague to Courtmacsherry and initial impressions of Elephone Explorer Pro</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.com/2016/10/02/timoleague-courtmacsherry-elephone-explorer-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 18:45:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.com/2016/10/02/timoleague-courtmacsherry-elephone-explorer-pro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of my fave things to do is watch videos made by Ultra Marathon runners and videographers. The views are always stunning and instantly make me want to go out for a run. My first attempt to do similar in Run Forest Run was a bit of a disaster as the rain killed my phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve had an action camera for a few years that my bro-in-law kindly gave us. It&amp;rsquo;s a Contour GPS. I love the GPS aspect of it but the lack of a screen, the weirdness with the bluetooth and the inability to use SD cards bigger than 2GB meant we didn&amp;rsquo;t use it much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to get something new but didn&amp;rsquo;t want to dish out $499 for a GoPro Hero 4 (and now 5) when I might not use it that much. I was very impressed by the reviews of the Yi 2 but that&amp;rsquo;s still $279. There are a ton of &amp;lt;$100 ones on all of the Chinese sites with SJCam probably being the best known, but the video quality in general looked horrendous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then 2 weeks ago whilst checking out some recent ones on Gearbest, I found the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gearbest.com/action-cameras/pp_314991.html&#34;&gt;Elephone Explorer Pro&lt;/a&gt;. Unlike most of the other brands, these seem to be a serious company with a range of phones too. The various review and unboxing videos I found all looked pretty good and if they are telling the truth, they are using a Sony sensor with a Novatek NTK96660 chipset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/elecam_03.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Elephone Explorer Pro&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course I&amp;rsquo;m not clueless and ignored the 4K claims. It&amp;rsquo;s just 1080p scaled up. But I was happy to go for 1080p60 on a device that cost less than $100 and came with all the bits you&amp;rsquo;d want like a waterproof case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made the rookie error of using DHL delivery, so of course it got caught in Irish customs and I had to pay VAT and Import duty of more than €30 but it&amp;rsquo;s still good value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today it had it&amp;rsquo;s first outing as I ran the lovely route from Timoleague to Courtmacsherry and back. I took multiple video clips and photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Main thoughts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Damn it&amp;rsquo;s small! I love that&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/elecam_01.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Small&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No problem taking a 32GB SD Card&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The remote control is great and has different buttons for video and stills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I zip-tied the remote control to the selfie-stick (the stick makes video less wobbly)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The screen is rubbish so it&amp;rsquo;s hard to see in sunlight whether video is recording or not&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a status led but it&amp;rsquo;s tiny so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t help&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The waterproof case seems great but I haven&amp;rsquo;t tried it properly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The bunch of adapters is also great but the back-mount is strange since it has a camera mount, not a GoPro one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It seems to be roughly the same size as a GoPro Hero &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; and I could 3D print a case for it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/elecam_02.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Case&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I hope I forgot to charge the battery fully since it barely did 20 mins of recording before dying (will test more)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Images aren&amp;rsquo;t bad&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/2016_1002_102341_003.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Timoleague1&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/2016_1002_103207_007.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Timoleague2&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/2016_1002_104122_002.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Timoleague3&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/2016_1002_104234_005.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Timoleague4&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;170 degree view is good&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The video below was taken with it in the waterproof case. I don&amp;rsquo;t know how much of an effect that has, apart from all the JJ Abrams lens flare. You can decide yourself if it&amp;rsquo;s good enough. I had the &amp;ldquo;gyroscope&amp;rdquo; feature enabled which seemed to help with wobble.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Music is &lt;a href=&#34;http://freemusicarchive.org/music/Lobo_Loco/20160910195925002/Lobo_Loco_-_09_-_Path_of_no_return_1385&#34;&gt;Path of no return&lt;/a&gt; by Lobo Loco. Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives 4.0 License.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/GTCRi8aBWuI&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;However, comparing to the source, that generated file is much lower quality. Most of the pixellation seems to have been caused by Pinnacle Studio, rather than YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/2016_1002_101235_007.MP4&#34;&gt;One of the source files&lt;/a&gt; for comparison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE 1: I did another run on the Lusitania Trail this morning and it&amp;rsquo;s proven that the battery is a bad joke. From full charge I got 10 minutes recording time whilst it was powered up for one hour, before it shut down with low battery. That&amp;rsquo;s completely useless. I&amp;rsquo;ll be asking for a replacement battery from GearBest now as hopefully it&amp;rsquo;s not a design flaw in the camera. I&amp;rsquo;ll post the video footage later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE 2: Looking at the video quality from today&amp;rsquo;s run, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty rubbish, even before Pinnacle pixellates it. Everything is either burnt out or too dark and its all blurry. I just compared it to some footage I took of the same location on the old Contour GPS a few months ago and the 5 year old Contour kicks its ass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See today&amp;rsquo;s:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/4CHjbieSGSI&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So do I have a dud camera or are my settings wrong or is this as good as it gets for &amp;lt;$100?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Berlin Marathon 2016 - A race for everyone in a great city</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.com/2016/10/02/the-berlin-marathon-2016-a-race-for-everyone-in-a-great-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 17:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.com/2016/10/02/the-berlin-marathon-2016-a-race-for-everyone-in-a-great-city/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our build up to Berlin had not been great. Between holidays, Red Hat Summit in SF, Red Hat Tech Exchange in Vietnam and a week of post-Vietnam illness, I only managed to get a few long runs in. D&amp;rsquo;wife also tripped whilst running, less than a week beforehand, and smashed her face up badly. But we had done the Clonakilty 10 Miler which we both felt went well. So we flew from Dublin the day before without too many nerves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As soon as I set foot in the Expo to collect race numbers etc, the nerves started. Marathon number seven, the fourth one this year, but I felt like it was my first. The rest of the day was taken up with Checkpoint Charlie, the deeply moving Memorial to the Murdered Jews of Europe and some of the worst service we&amp;rsquo;ve ever had &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tripadvisor.ie/Restaurant_Review-g187323-d7285098-Reviews-Vino_Basilico-Berlin.html&#34;&gt;in a restaurant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/2016-09-24%2011.51.32.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Memorial to the Murdered Jews of Europe&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/2016-09-24%2014.24.51.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Checkpoint Charlie&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A real highlight was the kids race on Saturday. Over 10,000 children took part, along with a bunch of teachers. I&amp;rsquo;d love to see the Dublin or Cork Marathons do the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/2016-09-24%2015.40.44.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Kid&#39;s Race&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hotel was barely a 10 minute walk to the start line. The number of people at the start line was nuts. Just like London. The buzz we got when they showed the elites taking off was fantastic. I&amp;rsquo;ve said it a few times on Twitter already, but in what other sport can anyone take part in the same race as the fastest people in the world by just paying your few quid entrance fee? I hope this never changes as it makes long distance running something very special indeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/2016-09-25%2017.18.52.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Start Line&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course is dead flat, which is why the world record is broken here so often. Sadly I didn&amp;rsquo;t break the record on this occasion. Maybe next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I loved the run. Despite the lack of prep and illness, I felt physically very strong the whole way around. I can&amp;rsquo;t say the same thing about my brain which took 17 miles to settle down and STFU. The drinks stations were mental but they always arrived just as I needed them. And whoever is responsible for putting warm sweet tea at the drinks station needs to be paid a massive bonus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The finish through Brandenburger Tor was one of those spine tingling moments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The German supporters were interesting. I found them a big help. There were lots of them (tho not at London levels) and they cheered lots. They also had music every mile or so which was fantastic, apart from the jazz obvs. But they don&amp;rsquo;t shout your name like they do in London. In fact the only people who did shout were Brits and Aussies!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got a Personal Best by only a few minutes (my Garmin data was garbage for some reason) and I felt pretty good within a few minutes of finishing, unlike Cork and Killarney where I was very wobbly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Multiple pints and currywurst later and I was sorted. Thanks to Eoghan and Sabrina for that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/2016-09-25%2017.46.14-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Currywurst&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highly recommended if you want to do a fast flat marathon in an iconic city.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/Ef8t8LXfRfI&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Walkist Manifesto - From Greenways to pathways everywhere and the future of Ireland&#39;s health</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.com/2016/09/21/greenways-byways-hedgerows-tourism-and-the-future-of-irelands-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 18:45:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.com/2016/09/21/greenways-byways-hedgerows-tourism-and-the-future-of-irelands-health/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I began this post several months ago. It started quite simply - I wanted to congratulate those behind the wonderful &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.deisegreenway.com/&#34;&gt;Waterford/Deise Greenway&lt;/a&gt; and encourage Cork County Council to embrace a West Cork Greenway and execute on it. The Waterford one is partially opening this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/bridge.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Waterford Greenway&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However the more I thought about it, the bigger the &amp;ldquo;vision&amp;rdquo; got. What I&amp;rsquo;m going to present here is obvious in many places, controversial in others and possibly pure fantasy. But we simply can&amp;rsquo;t continue to stagger blindly forward, as we have been doing for decades. It&amp;rsquo;s time for a fundamental change in how the infrastructure of this country is arranged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teddy Roosevelt, 1903:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are not building this country of ours for a day. It is to last through the ages. We stand on the threshold of a new century. We look into the dim years that rise before us, knowing that if we are true that the generations that succeed us here shall fall heir to a heritage such as has never been known before. I ask that we keep in mind not only our own interests, but the interests of our children. Any generation fit to do its work must work for the future, for the people of the future, as well as for itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;let-s-start-small-and-talk-local-first-bandon-and-clonakilty-paths&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start small and talk local first - Bandon and Clonakilty Paths&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running or walking in Bandon for health in an exercise in aggravation. I was really pleased when they decided to name a nice short walk by the river after Graham Norton and the old railway walk after Clare O&amp;rsquo;Leary. But it doesn&amp;rsquo;t look like a single person in the County Council thought it would be a good idea to connect the two of them together. So if you want to make use of the nearby railway walk, you either drive there (many do!) or you risk life and limb on a one-foot wide hard shoulder with cars racing by at 100+kph and regularly crashing into each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every road out of Bandon stops just as the houses do and leaves you in mortal danger if you want to go any further on foot. Anyone who cycles from Bandon to Innishannon is very brave indeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like many Irish towns, Bandon has a love-hate relationship with its river. It&amp;rsquo;s lovely in the few small places you can see it. But it&amp;rsquo;s a beast that has damaged the town too. That relationship was typified by the Bandon Half Marathon and 10K which was run for a few years without a single view of the river. I&amp;rsquo;m convinced a marathon along the river would attract big crowds. Imagine a Bandon to Kinsale run, via Innishannon, on a permanent river trail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Bandon is just one local symptom. Look at Clonakilty and Inchydoney. A beach rated as the best in Ireland by Trip Advisor users has a path out towards it that stops at exactly one mile. From then on, grit your teeth and hope some moron doesn&amp;rsquo;t plough you down if you want to walk or run the remaining miles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the rest of the country is exactly the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some bright lights - look at the ring road in Kilkenny any evening. It&amp;rsquo;s jammed with people walking and running. Why? Because they can travel everywhere safely on foot. Literally if you build it they will come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Public Bike Scheme in cities also shows what happens when you provide the facilities and infrastructure. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.irishexaminer.com/breakingnews/ireland/public-bike-scheme-numbers-show-cycling-is-becoming-more-popular-751422.html?utm_source=iosapp&amp;amp;utm_medium=share&amp;amp;utm_campaign=sharebutton&#34;&gt;Public bike scheme numbers show cycling is becoming more popular&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;waterford-greenway&#34;&gt;Waterford Greenway&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier in the year I heard about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.deisegreenway.com/&#34;&gt;Waterford Greenway&lt;/a&gt; and got very excited. The idea of being able to safely run, walk or cycle from Waterford to Dungarvan along the old railway line struck me as inspirational. I&amp;rsquo;m still shocked it has actually happened. I&amp;rsquo;ve been on it three times now, ahead of its completion and it far exceeds every expectation I had. The views are stunning, the terrain changes all the time and everything about it puts a huge smile on my face. Given how many people I&amp;rsquo;ve met on the Greenway in its unfinished state, I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see it when it&amp;rsquo;s finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/CszYeE4XgAEnIq6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Waterford Greenway 2&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important thing about the Greenway (and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.greenway.ie/&#34;&gt;Great Western one&lt;/a&gt; and the upcoming &lt;a href=&#34;http://candlgreenway.ie/&#34;&gt;Cavan/Leitrim one&lt;/a&gt;) is that it&amp;rsquo;s a facility for everyone, not just tourists. And that idea became the heart of my thoughts on this wider topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;west-cork-greenway&#34;&gt;West Cork Greenway&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cork CoCo has a &amp;ldquo;policy&amp;rdquo; of creating a West Cork Greenway. An &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.corkcoco.ie/co/pdf/562780142.pdf&#34;&gt;excellent study&lt;/a&gt; (warning direct PDF link) was carried out in 2011, which figured out the how, where and cost. But nothing has happened. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to particularly slag off the new not-Alcatraz in the the middle of a freezing cold harbour, as it seems to be off to a good start in peak tourist season. But no one is travelling to Cork to see that. Imagine spending all of that money instead on a perspex enclosed walk across a refurbished Chetwynd Viaduct followed by a renovated Ballinhassig tunnel. It would rightly become world famous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;joining-the-dots&#34;&gt;Joining the dots&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now think about an East Cork Greenway. And a New Ross Greenway. And a Rosslare Greenway. And a Dublin to Wexford Greenway. Imagine being able to safely travel on foot or bike from Dublin to Wexford to Waterford to Cork to Barley Cove to Glengarrif to Kenmare to Killarney to Tralee and Dingle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dammit, build a walking trail around the entire coast of Ireland. Something to make the whole world wake up and pay attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It looks like Northern Ireland has the right idea. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.com/news/uk-northern-ireland-37355509&#34;&gt;NI greenways: 600-mile network could get Stormont green light&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-wild-atlantic-way&#34;&gt;The Wild Atlantic Way&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been extremely impressed with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wildatlanticway.com/home&#34;&gt;Wild Atlantic Way&lt;/a&gt; marketing campaign. Hell, they make me want to move to Ireland and I live here. But that&amp;rsquo;s all it is, a marketing campaign. The only obvious capital spend outside of marketing is for signage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The core problem is that they show all these amazing places you can visit in Ireland and every single one of them requires you to drive there (or risk your neck cycling), since walking or running there would be suicidal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We live on a stunning beautiful island. The Wild Atlantic Way should be The Wild Irish way for all of us, not just tourists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What percentage of the Wild Atlantic Way is car-free vs &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u4QeHPn0NWI&#34;&gt;The West Highland Way&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/R8DeYWxmtnc&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;national-parks&#34;&gt;National Parks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a long section and after Greenways was supposed to be the bulk of this post. But it just made me have even bigger ideas. So bear with me, we&amp;rsquo;ll get there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2016 is the Centennial of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nps.gov/subjects/centennial/index.htm&#34;&gt;US National Parks Service&lt;/a&gt; and they are doing a wonderful job promoting that fact. My only experiences of them was a day in Yosemite in 1996 and a day in Grand Canyon in 1998 and both are ingrained on my mind forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start by comparing the mission statement of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.npws.ie/national-parks&#34;&gt;Irish National Parks and Wildlife Service&lt;/a&gt; and the US National Parks Service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the policy of the Department of Arts, Heritage, Regional, Rural and Gaeltacht Affairs, endorsed by successive governments, to abide by the criteria and standards for National Parks as set by the IUCN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;vs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The National Park Service preserves unimpaired the natural and cultural resources and values of the National Park System for the enjoyment, education, and inspiration of this and future generations. The Park Service cooperates with partners to extend the benefits of natural and cultural resource conservation and outdoor recreation throughout this country and the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesus. Are you as depressed as I was when I read the Irish one?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to Google to find out if we even had a National Parks service. I have been in one and to be fair, it&amp;rsquo;s bloody brilliant - Killarney National Park. Check my earlier post on my Marathon there. But I&amp;rsquo;ve also done the Half Marathon down from Moll&amp;rsquo;s Gap. The park is just fantastic. And in keeping with my theme, was full of both tourists and locals when I was there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been some very positive things happening around the National Parks. The government &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ahrrga.gov.ie/expansion-of-the-wicklow-mountains-national-park/&#34;&gt;bought 5000 acres&lt;/a&gt; in Wicklow that NAMA was trying to hawk to some vulture funds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But why do we only have six parks? Why not one in every county? Why aren&amp;rsquo;t we buying up land that is of minimal agricultural use and using it in the style of the Americans? Roughly &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.irunfar.com/2016/08/a-trail-runners-primer-on-public-lands.html&#34;&gt;640 million acres&lt;/a&gt;, or almost a third of the US, fall under the auspices of the federal government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obama gets it, why don&amp;rsquo;t we?

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/djDx6LKRFdQ&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/doodles/celebrating-us-national-parks&#34;&gt;Google also gets it&lt;/a&gt;, why don&amp;rsquo;t we?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s stop playing with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ahrrga.gov.ie/e4-455-million-approved-by-minister-ring-for-75-rural-recreation-projects/&#34;&gt;mickey-mouse Rural Recreation funding&lt;/a&gt;, welcome tho it is, and do this right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;pedestrian-hostile-in-two-generations&#34;&gt;Pedestrian hostile in two generations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hillwalkers and outdoorsey people are a very specific segment. We need to be casting the net much wider and make walking the default for everyone, not the exception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How did we go in two generations from being a piss poor country that couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford cars to one which is actively pedestrian hostile? We went from every kid cycling or walking to school and even university to almost zero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why did we sleepwalk into this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The World Health Organization estimates that 1.25 million people die from car-related injuries per year. Half of the deaths are pedestrians, bicyclists, and motorcyclists hit by cars. Cars are the leading cause of death for people ages 15–29 years old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s not forget cyclists who are regularly killed. The recent decision in Dublin to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thejournal.ie/cycling-greenways-2964771-Sep2016/&#34;&gt;postpone the bicycle greenways&lt;/a&gt; does not bode well for anything I&amp;rsquo;m proposing here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a positive note, in Cork &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eveningecho.ie/cork-news/councils-get-gear-cycle-tracks/2524009/&#34;&gt;COUNCILS GET INTO GEAR FOR MORE CYCLE TRACKS&lt;/a&gt;. A blueprint for the development of new cycle lanes and tracks across Cork city and its suburbs has been published jointly by Cork city and county councils.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;health&#34;&gt;Health&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are lots of people trying to do good work around health and fitness here, in the private, public and quango sectors. But it&amp;rsquo;s mostly siloed, piecemeal or, in the case of something like National Fitness Day, tokenistic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE 2: A great example of looking like you are doing something but really just ticking boxes is &lt;a href=&#34;http://health.gov.ie/blog/press-release/ministers-launch-a-healthy-weight-for-ireland-obesity-policy-and-action-plan-2016-2025/&#34;&gt;A Healthy Weight for Ireland: Obesity Policy and Action Plan 2016-2025&lt;/a&gt;. Even the most naive of us go into full eyeroll mode when we see press releases that prattle on about guidelines, forums and stakeholders. The only surprise is that they didn&amp;rsquo;t announce another taskforce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, a great example of actually doing something practical is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.parkrun.com/&#34;&gt;Parkrun&lt;/a&gt; movement. A recent tweet by the organisation in the UK said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A whopping 92,432 people crossed a parkrun finish line in the UK this weekend&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is that 92k is not whopping in a country of 64 million people where 62% of people are overweight or obese. A more fundamental change is needed rather than events which will never be more than niche for people who already want to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And whilst it&amp;rsquo;s great to see Coillte adding things like Zipit in Farran wood, it costs money to use those things. It also costs money to park there. And you&amp;rsquo;d be suicidal to try and get there on foot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Health shouldn&amp;rsquo;t require wealth.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t a new problem. In 1963 JFK was horrified by the stats he saw about the declining fitness of young people. He kicked off a range of initiatives including a set of 50 mile events which were hugely popular that year. RFK even completed a 50 miler. But then JFK was assassinated. Very quickly the events petered out and now there is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jfk50mile.org/history/&#34;&gt;only one 50 miler left&lt;/a&gt;. Which someday I hope to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do we get the people who need to move the most moving, but who are least likely to do so?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What percentage of our multi-billion-Euro health budget is spent dealing with preventable no-exercise related diseases?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things like Autonomous cars are only going to make things worse. Do we really want to end up like L.A. Story?&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/3gP_ErrRILk&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE 3: As an aside, I completely agree with &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/thoughtwax/status/778915462683979776&#34;&gt;@thoughtwax&lt;/a&gt; that&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;autonomous cars will present a once in a lifetime opportunity to reclaim public space for people&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we are 100% autonomous, driving related deaths should also drop to almost zero. And drink driving becomes a thing of the past. It could even herald the return of the rural pub. But I&amp;rsquo;m still concerned that an always-available fleet of autonomous Uber vehicles will have us all eventually looking like characters out of Wall-E.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a great piece in the Irish Times on obesity. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.irishtimes.com/sport/ian-o-riordan-we-are-sports-mad-but-sanity-needed-to-tackle-obesity-1.2794132#.V9xTtrZY9qI.twitter&#34;&gt;Ian O’Riordan: We are sports mad but sanity needed to tackle obesity&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed there is something strangely contradictory about all this talk of overweight adults and children and the rise of obesity, which according to some reports, will be hovering somewhere around 90 per cent of the population by 2030, the highest projected level Europe. You don’t need me to repeat the scary thought that one in four Irish children is now considered to be overweight, because for a country that prides itself on being so mad about sport, that makes little sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sidenote-dogs-and-dog-shit&#34;&gt;Sidenote - Dogs and dog shit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m getting to the point where I think dogs need to be temporarily banned from all public footpaths until a large proportion of their idiot owners stop behaving like 12th century peasants throwing their shit out onto the street.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pick up your dogs&amp;rsquo; shit and put your dog on a goddammed leash, you morons. I&amp;rsquo;ve had two little unleashed runt-sized dogs snapping at my heels recently when out on runs. The next one gets a kick in the face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Waterford is thinking of banning dogs from the Greenway. Given that it&amp;rsquo;s already riddled with dog shit before it&amp;rsquo;s open, they are 100% right. On one of my runs there, a woman had a large dog on a harness and struggled to control it as it tried to jump at me and attack me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there&amp;rsquo;s actually a revenue opportunity here. Dog-walking arenas. Places that dog-owners can go to walk their dogs, step in each others shit and break up the dog-fights. Lots of farmers could create these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping that responsible reasonable dog owners shame the idiots into behaving properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;france&#34;&gt;France&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;France has lots of problems but seems to have some vision for walkers. We went to a holiday/caravan park in Marennes this year, south of La Rochelle, for the second time. Many people who go to these kind of places never leave the camp except maybe to drive to the supermarket. I know we&amp;rsquo;ve been guilty of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year I decided to be different and went for two runs in the locality. I was, to be honest, a bit worried beforehand, as I didn&amp;rsquo;t know the roads at all. Some Google Streetview calmed me. On my first run, I did a short 4km loop around some back roads. And it was an absolute joy. Why? No damned hedges and a grass verge that was flush with the road. Plenty of the usual little white French vans passed me but [a] I could see them coming for ages and [b] I could take a small step sideways to be 100% safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/verge.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;France Verge&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my second run, I went much further afield and was thrilled to discover an offical nature trail. This was created just with basic crushed white rock and was a lovely surface to run on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/20160723_083535.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;France 2&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The return leg was on a very busy road. But again, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a problem. No hedges, and big flat verge. We&amp;rsquo;ll get back to hedges in a moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it&amp;rsquo;s not just summer holiday locations where the French are looking at this. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.citylab.com/design/2015/05/in-paris-plans-for-a-river-seine-reinvention/392639/&#34;&gt;In Paris, Plans for a Seine Reinvention&lt;/a&gt;. Mayor Anne Hidalgo has announced an &amp;ldquo;almost philosophical project&amp;rdquo; to take the famed river&amp;rsquo;s quayside back from cars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile in Dublin&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thejournal.ie/cycling-greenways-2964771-Sep2016/&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;It&amp;rsquo;s bananas!&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt; Fury as funding pulled for Dublin cycling projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;re-forestation-wildlands-wetlands&#34;&gt;Re-forestation, Wildlands, Wetlands&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This bit is critical for the next bit. We need a massive re-forestion of the country and the annexing of large areas for wildlife and plants. Every idle bit of land and farmland should be planted with native species (not poxy pines obviously). This is not for commercial purposes, tho that needn&amp;rsquo;t be excluded in all cases. It ties into the National Park idea but more importantly, it gives wildlife and birds somewhere permanent away from the regular cutting of hedgerows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And before you tell me that it will take decades, &lt;a href=&#34;https://gearjunkie.com/india-plants-50-million-trees-one-day&#34;&gt;India Plants 50 million trees in one day&lt;/a&gt;. Or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2016/aug/07/national-forest-woodland-midlands-regeneration&#34;&gt;How millions of trees brought a broken landscape back to life&lt;/a&gt;.
It&amp;rsquo;s that vision thing again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hedgerows&#34;&gt;Hedgerows&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK, now for the controversial bit that I&amp;rsquo;m sure you saw coming. It&amp;rsquo;s time to get rid of all our our roadside hedgerows and ditches. All of them. Wait, wait, before you blow a gasket and start calling me names. First, we need that massive re-forestation programme to ensure that birds and wildlife have somewhere to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main impediment to people being able to walk safely everywhere is [a] visibility and [b] having somewhere to put their feet. The removal of all hedges and the covering over of all ditches deals with this. I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed a lot of ditch covering locally on small roads recently, but of course it&amp;rsquo;s not being done in a way that anyone could actually walk on. So this is eminently possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do one of the loops of the wonderful &lt;a href=&#34;http://conoroneill.com/2016/08/26/the-seven-heads-walk-and-lusitania-trail-is-one-of-west-corks-best-kept-secrets/&#34;&gt;Lusitania Trail&lt;/a&gt;, this is the road you have to walk back on, with cars whizzing by at 100kph. It&amp;rsquo;s not something I would ever do by choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/irish_roads.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Irish Roads&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government should CPO every roadside ditch and hedge. This removes the current nonsense where hedge cuttting is the landowners responsibility and can only happen during certain months due to nests. Get rid of the lot and the birds can go back to their natural pre-road habitats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE 1: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.heritagecouncil.ie/county-heritage-services/news/view-article/article/new-initiatives-launched-to-safeguard-irelands-unique-hedgerows/&#34;&gt;A good link&lt;/a&gt; from my sister around a new initiative to safeguard hedgerows in Ireland. Just to be clear, I&amp;rsquo;m talking about creating far more hedgerows and wilderness areas than we have now, just not beside roads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-new-ireland&#34;&gt;A New Ireland&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has been a very long run up to the idea that a whole new outlook is needed in Ireland. We need a grand revolutionary vision and plan for the health of our people and then the execution of that plan quickly. It can&amp;rsquo;t be years of consultants reports and local government jollies and civil servant conservatism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do the current generation of politicians and public servants in this country want to be forgotten in a few short years due to being bench-warmers who think keeping a steady hand on the tiller is their only job? Or do they want to be like Teddy Roosevelt, JFK, Donagh O&amp;rsquo;Malley and T. K. Whitaker, still being talked about decades later?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course we can&amp;rsquo;t do a &amp;ldquo;big bang deployment&amp;rdquo;, as we say in software. It has to be iterative but based on a core set of principles. We could start tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every child should be able to walk and cycle safely to school. Build pathways to every school in the country spreading out like a spider&amp;rsquo;s web&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move all religious education to after-school opt-in per religion. Replace all of that school time with outdoor activities, no matter what the weather.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everyone should be able to walk and cycle safely from every town to every town in this country&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give pedestrians the Right of Way by default everywhere. Cars must stop if you want to cross the road. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.economist.com/blogs/economist-explains/2014/02/economist-explains-16&#34;&gt;Why Sweden has so few road deaths&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everyone from the Dept of Env, County/City Councils, HSE, NRA, OPW, Coillte and every relevant department and quango are told exactly how they are going to be part of the solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In advance of a massive buy-up of land for the National Parks, do a huge expansion of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.housing.gov.ie/community/rural-development/walks-scheme/walks-scheme&#34;&gt;Walks Scheme&lt;/a&gt; to make trails available everywhere&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start major re-forestation immediately&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start removing all hedgerows on major roads initially&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes this will eventually be a grand building program and require large capital investment. For the pathways, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be expensive pavement or tarmac or cobble lock everywhere. Crushed hard core is sufficient. But it also can&amp;rsquo;t be a poxy white line painted on a road with a few &amp;ldquo;caution pedestrians&amp;rdquo; signs. The criminal negligence of Irish drivers at pelican crossings makes that unacceptable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;paying-for-it&#34;&gt;Paying for it&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how to pay for all of this? Let&amp;rsquo;s start with no new road building. Divert all of those funds to the building of pathways and trails. Look, I hate the roads to Killarney and Limerick as much as you do. And as for Dunkettle! But I&amp;rsquo;m talking about something a lot more important than a few extra minutes driving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The removal of the hedgerows will deal with a large number of traffic accidents that happen here when idiots overtake blind on country roads. That&amp;rsquo;s a positive feedback loop that will help pay for itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The top causes of death in Ireland are all lifestyle diseases:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coronary heart disease 8%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heart attack 8%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lung cancer 6%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;COPD 5%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pull several hundred million out of the health budget that is currently being spent on dealing with preventable lifestyle-related illnesses. Provide cheap runners and step trackers to everyone who is capable of curing themselves, instead of rip-off statins and other heart meds. Carrot and Stick. Or carrot and vape for the smokers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there are also revenue oportunities. Figures from Fáilte Ireland show that in 2014, close to 1.2 million visitors to Ireland took part in hiking or cross country walking. These activity tourists spent in the region of €915 million in the Irish economy during their stay. Other stats show that 286,000 visitors took part in cycling activities with a spend of €268 million. These two sectors combined generated revenue for the Irish economy in the region of €1.2 billion in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is in a country that&amp;rsquo;s actively hostile to both walkers and cyclists!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine how much revenue we could generate if we made their lives easy? All related taxes should be used to pay for the above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;but-but-but-this-is-how-things-have-always-been&#34;&gt;But, but, but, this is how things have always been&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;..in your lifetime. A pre-famine landscape looked nothing like it does now. A pre-deforestation landscape looked nothing like it does now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any time big changes are suggested I&amp;rsquo;m reminded of Douglas Adams on technology:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve come up with a set of rules that describe our reactions to technologies:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anything that is in the world when you’re born is normal and ordinary and is just a natural part of the way the world works.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anything that&amp;rsquo;s invented between when you’re fifteen and thirty-five is new and exciting and revolutionary and you can probably get a career in it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anything invented after you&amp;rsquo;re thirty-five is against the natural order of things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A plan like this addresses health, jobs, tourism, taxes and the environment. Ireland could be leading the way in Europe. Just like we did with fags and bags but with 100x the long term benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The health crisis in Ireland reminds me a bit of global warming. It happens so gradually that the average person doesn&amp;rsquo;t realise the frog is being boiled. Unlike global warming, it&amp;rsquo;s not too late to deal with this health problem. But it&amp;rsquo;s going to take an incredibly strong will to do so. Sadly, I don&amp;rsquo;t think we have anyone in a position of power in this country capable of making it happen. So the best I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to do is make sure my kids are healthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;thoughts&#34;&gt;Thoughts?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drop them in the comments box below. Always interested in views no matter how much they oppose my own. No safe spaces here. The only rule is that we keep it civil.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tough as Leather - The Story of Sporting Legend John Lenihan</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.com/2016/09/19/tough-as-leather-john-lenihan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 18:53:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.com/2016/09/19/tough-as-leather-john-lenihan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Finally a book review on the blog. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure where I heard about this book, probably Twitter, but damn it&amp;rsquo;s a great story. I&amp;rsquo;d never heard of John Lenihan until 3 weeks ago. Then I read this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.irishtimes.com/sport/other-sports/tough-as-leather-john-lenihan-the-conqueror-of-carrauntoohil-1.2273089&#34;&gt;Irish Times article&lt;/a&gt; and my jaw was on the floor. He has not only won the Carrauntoohil mountain race 19 times, he still holds the record of 1 hour 11 minutes and 43 seconds. Read that again. Up and down the highest mountain in Ireland in 1:11:43. Holy shit the man is a running machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/runforestrun/CsLX2RxWAAUssQO.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Tough as Leather&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His story is genuinely interesting and he comes across as a honourable talented hard-working man who will probably never get the adulation he deserves. The writing itself is very pedestrian but that&amp;rsquo;s ok, the story is strong enough to carry it. A recommended read if you have any interest in running, striving or making hard choices. You can &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bookdepository.com/Tough-Leather-John-Lenihan/9781782805045&#34;&gt;buy it on Book Depository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Altra Lone Peak 3.0 first impressions</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.com/2016/09/19/altra-lone-peak-30-first-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 18:43:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.com/2016/09/19/altra-lone-peak-30-first-impressions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve done my first trail race, it&amp;rsquo;s time for my initial impressions of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.altrarunning.com/men/lone-peak-30&#34;&gt;Altra Lone Peak 3.0&lt;/a&gt;. Back in June I got a pair of LP 2.5 in &lt;a href=&#34;https://sports-basement.myshopify.com/pages/store-sf-bryant-street/&#34;&gt;Sports Basement&lt;/a&gt; in San Francisco. They were supposed to be my first pair of trail runners but I found them so comfy they immediately became my daily shoes. When I went to get another pair in Europe I learned that they were about to be replaced with the 3.0. If you can find any pairs of 2.5, grab them, they are a complete bargain now and very different to the 3.0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best place I found to get the 3.0 on this side of the pond was &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.accelerateuk.com/shop/product/21/Mountain--Trail-and-Fell/Altra-ZeroDrop-Lone-Peak-3-0/&#34;&gt;Accelerate UK&lt;/a&gt;. They sent me one of the first pairs they got last week. They look completely different to the 2.5 and TBH are a bit generic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/runforestrun/A1653_Orange_btn4_xl.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;LP30 Clean&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main changes, apart from looks are a smaller &amp;ldquo;last&amp;rdquo; and a grippier sole. Whilst the 2.5 are a bit loose on me, the 3.0 is snug and a perfect fit with the usual Altra benefits of wide toe-box, high stack and zero drop. I was concerned when I did a short first run on them on the treadmill that my left arch hurt a lot. The insole at the arch seems to be very high on these. Much higher than any other Altras.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the real test came yesterday during Run Forest Run and they were fantastic. The fit on my foot remained great, the arch pain was gone and the grip was incredible on all of the surfaces. Just a warning that whilst they are trail shoes, they are not waterproof as I quickly discovered. Irish puddles, yay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/runforestrun/lone_peak_30.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;LP30&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know lots of other people have the same criticism of Altra that I do. I love their products but this sizing nonsense has to stop. It&amp;rsquo;s bad enough that two of your products fit completely differently for the same nominal size, but when you are doing it between versions of the same product, it&amp;rsquo;s just ridiculous! From what I can see, every review of the 3.0 on the Altra site is complaining about the sizing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in summary - I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of the LP 3.0. But go 1 Euro size up from your usual running shoes. Unfortunately no one in Ireland seems to sell them so, if they don&amp;rsquo;t fit, you may be in the usual world of product returns cost hell that we suffer from over here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run Forest Run trail race report. Loved it!</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.com/2016/09/19/run-forest-run-trail-race-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 18:33:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.com/2016/09/19/run-forest-run-trail-race-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you may have read in my previous post, I&amp;rsquo;ve been dipping my toe into running off-road. The phrase &amp;ldquo;trail running&amp;rdquo; still seems pretty rare in Ireland where I see &amp;ldquo;mountain running&amp;rdquo; mentioned more often, and &amp;ldquo;fell running&amp;rdquo; in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week my wife spotted on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://corkrunning.blogspot.ie/&#34;&gt;Running in Cork blog&lt;/a&gt; that there was a trail run on in Castlefreke/Rathbarry on Sunday 18th called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/Run-Forest-Run-175750705775650/?fref=ts&#34;&gt;Run Forest Run&lt;/a&gt;. It instantly got me interested as it was [a] nearby and [b] only 5 miles long. I have just spent 11 days sick on and off after a trip to Vietnam. Top tip - don&amp;rsquo;t brush your teeth with the tap-water, even in a high-end hotel. I&amp;rsquo;m doing the Berlin Marathon next Sunday, so the big question I wanted to answer yesterday was &amp;ldquo;am I well enough for Berlin yet?&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the laugh I asked my 14yo and the 17yo sons if they wanted to do it with me. I was shocked when they both said yes. Their mother then added the sweetener of €20 for the winner between the three of us. Neither of them have done much more than a bit of running in school, so I was very impressed by their enthusiasm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see the Strava route and Ordnance Survey map below. A lovely mix of path, trail, road, forest and beach in a beautiful part of West Cork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/runforestrun/run_forest_run_route.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Route1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/runforestrun/14224702_1430913196926055_7696748586087695054_n.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Route2&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, Sunday morning welcomed us with lashing rain. But what the hell, in for a penny, in for €20. The start/finish was the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.galleyflash.com/&#34;&gt;Galleyflash Rowing Club&lt;/a&gt; on Kilkern lake. A few people were there when we arrived and sadly the numbers didn&amp;rsquo;t really grow. In the end, they dropped the 5km and only 19 of us lined out for the 5 miler. I figure there were three reasons for turnout: [1] the rotten weather [2] the Charleville Half Marathon with nearly 1000 people was on the same day and [3] the lack of much publicity for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/runforestrun/20160918_113913.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lake&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we didn&amp;rsquo;t mind in the slightest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/runforestrun/20160918_115939.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Start&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Off we went and we quickly ended up at the back of the field. But the two boys looked solid and we were doing a decent pace for n00bs. They slowed down a bit going into Castlefreke Woods and then grinded to a slow walk going up the first hill in the woods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/runforestrun/20160918_121814.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Woods&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We picked the pace back-up and did the road stretch quickly. Then on to the nasty-assed hill up to the large cross.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/runforestrun/20160918_124653.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Hill&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boys were struggling with tiredness and calf pain and they claimed to have found god at this point ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/runforestrun/20160918_124928.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cross&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The downhill was brilliant fun and we ran the whole thing. Here&amp;rsquo;s a video which gives some sense of the fantastic location and views. Apologies for the relentless heavy breathing.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/_NhKnpDfQXI&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The final mile on the beach was brilliantly horrific with huge patches of soft sand you couldn&amp;rsquo;t avoid. Then back on to the road for a bit and to the Rowing club. The 14yo came in first of us, having found a great second wind. The 17yo hurt his achilles on the beach and came in last. But I was incredibly proud of them both. 8.4km is no joke off-road in the lashing rain when you have done no training for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tea and biccies sorted us out before we drove home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really want to thank the organisers and helpers for a superb event. Everything was absolutely top notch from the signage to the stewards. I&amp;rsquo;d particularly call out the young guy at the end of the beach who had to stand there watching 3 slowly moving bodies in the rain for an interminable duration so he could tell us where to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be making lots of noise about this event next year to try and drive up the numbers. Honestly, even if you&amp;rsquo;ve never run before, you&amp;rsquo;ll love this route and the terrain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imra.ie/events/details/id/1339/&#34;&gt;IMRA also did an event here&lt;/a&gt; in February. I&amp;rsquo;m aiming to do that if it&amp;rsquo;s on next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you know of any other trail events like this in West Cork, do let me know!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh and yes, I think I&amp;rsquo;ll be fine for Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update 1: There is now a &lt;a href=&#34;http://corkrunning.blogspot.ie/2016/09/results-photos-of-run-forest-run-5m-in.html&#34;&gt;Running in Cork post&lt;/a&gt; about it and a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/Run-Forest-Run-175750705775650/photos/?tab=album&amp;amp;album_id=1445859345431440&#34;&gt;gallery of pics on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Seven Heads Walk, Fuschia Walk and Lusitania Trail is one of West Cork&#39;s best kept secrets. Just go.</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.com/2016/08/26/the-seven-heads-walk-and-lusitania-trail-is-one-of-west-corks-best-kept-secrets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 19:32:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.com/2016/08/26/the-seven-heads-walk-and-lusitania-trail-is-one-of-west-corks-best-kept-secrets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shortly after we moved to Bandon, over 10 years ago, I bought a bunch of Ordnance Survey maps of the area and two books by Damien Enright called &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Walks-Courtmacsherry-Seven-Damien-Enright/dp/1902631005&#34;&gt;Walks of Courtmacsherry Bay &amp;amp; The Seven Heads&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Walks in and around Kinsale&amp;rdquo;. We had high hopes of being outdoorsy. To our shame, the most we ever did was to haul the kids along the short track in Kilbrittain woods, the even shorter one in Ballinspittle woods and the tiny bit longer one in Dromillihy woods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lack of places to safely walk in West Cork outside of towns is ridiculous. I have a separate monster blogpost coming that includes this topic. It&amp;rsquo;s a cracker. But this one is about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sevenheadspeninsula.ie/&#34;&gt;The Seven Heads&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/3QOn-AdXV_s&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve recently become very interested in the whole idea of trail running. By interested I mean I watch huge numbers of YouTube videos about it and revel in the incredible achievements of people who do races like &lt;a href=&#34;http://barkleymovie.com/&#34;&gt;The Barkley Marathons&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://utmbmontblanc.com/en/&#34;&gt;UTMB (Ultra Trail de Mont Blanc)&lt;/a&gt; which started two hours ago. But a few weeks ago I finally decided I wanted to make some sort of attempt at doing it myself. Of course I had to do a pre-run, so I hauled the smaller kids out to Courtmac and the start of what now seems to be more formally called The Lusitania Trail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I did when dragged on walks by my parents, they hated every step. I loved every minute. The route was basically the first recommended short loop. You can read all the details over on the superb pages on &lt;a href=&#34;http://explorewestcork.ie/walking/seven-heads-walk/&#34;&gt;Explore West Cork&lt;/a&gt;. In fact I printed out their directions and made a copy of that section of Map 87. In reality you need none of that, since the whole thing is now signposted as The Lusitania Trail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the ever-changing views that make this such a spectacular walk. You begin in Courtmac, then into woods with beautiful little slipways down to the water, then suddenly the first gobsmacking headland and the Atlantic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty easy walk apart from places where the cows have mushed the ground up badly. Lots of stiles separate the fields and it&amp;rsquo;s completely safe. The Fuschia Walk is absolutely beautiful and you come back through the lovely Ramsey Hill cottages and then on footpath all the way to Courtmac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-08-07%2010.54.36.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Leaving Woods&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-08-07%2010.54.50.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;First Look&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was so delighted with our trip that I vowed to come back. A few weeks passed and I repeated the route but started in Timoleague and ran most of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-08-07%2010.04.42.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Timoleague&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was tough on the ankles in places but the weather was fantastic so I didn&amp;rsquo;t need trail runners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-08-07%2010.54.54.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ankles&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two weeks later I was back again. This time it was a 15 mile loop that again started in Timoleague. I found that the written directions on Explore West Cork were very hard to follow and I did a lot of recce via Google Maps and the Ordnance Survey map in advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-08-07%2011.06.28.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Woods&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-08-07%2011.06.54.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Woods2&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, yet again, the entire route was signposted and took almost no thinking on my part. The only place I got confused was on Broadstrand where you have to go the entire length of the beach before you see the steps back up to the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-08-07%2011.27.55.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Meelmane&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-08-07%2011.31.20.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Broadstrand&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-08-07%2011.43.00.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Statue&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is one very steep path up along some fields and then an old pre-Famine road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-08-07 11.52.16.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Start famine Road&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which eventually brings you out to this amazing view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-08-07%2012.09.01.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Headlands&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got to Narry&amp;rsquo;s Cross and then I returned along some very quiet roads via Lislee and a busy main road back into Courtmacsherry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-08-07%2012.42.17.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lislee&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-08-07%2012.52.43.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Main Road&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to take a breather there and have an ice-cream and Lucozade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-08-07%2013.13.27.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ice Cream&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then the final push back to the car in Timoleague.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I fully intend to go again soon and run the entire route which is heading towards Ultra Marathon length. Well, when I say run, I mean run-walk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason I wanted to write this post is that the Seven Heads walk is little more than a name for many people. It&amp;rsquo;s barely a 20 minute drive from Bandon. Probably less from Clonakilty. Much of it is completely off-road with no asshole drivers. If you are looking for some of the best views in the country and a bit of exercise, you owe it to yourself to check it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep an eye out for my next post which takes this basic topic and turns it into a very long rant about the future of the country&amp;rsquo;s health.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A year of running updates</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.com/2016/07/10/a-year-of-running-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2016 18:32:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.com/2016/07/10/a-year-of-running-updates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As has been the case so often over the past 15 years of blogging, I&amp;rsquo;ve been very remiss in my updates. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a ton of things I want to write about, like the Waterford Greenway and how adventure/outdoor tourism could be a much bigger business here. But that&amp;rsquo;s for my holidays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, as I move this blog to &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/]&#34;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; (what a journey it has had!), I thought I&amp;rsquo;d just give an update on my running. The last time I mentioned it, I had &lt;a href=&#34;http://conoroneill.com/2015/05/03/this-heavy-guy-decided-to-run-the-london-marathon-and-you-won-t-believe-what-happened-next/&#34;&gt;just finished the London Marathon&lt;/a&gt;. Still a life highlight for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of 2015 was quiet from a &amp;ldquo;race&amp;rdquo; perspective. I signed up for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dinglemarathon.ie/&#34;&gt;Dingle Marathon&lt;/a&gt; and then chickened out and did the Half. Very glad I did, as I&amp;rsquo;d forgotten what a tough course it is. But it is still one of the greatest routes anywhere on the planet. Even the Top Gear guys agree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://runclon.ie/&#34;&gt;Clon Half&lt;/a&gt; was delayed due to the flooding, so basically I spent most of 2015 doing short runs around the town and on the treadmill and making no impact on my weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So January 1st lands and we decide to really push it. We signed up for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.greatermanchestermarathon.com/&#34;&gt;Greater Manchester Marathon&lt;/a&gt; in April and kicked off training. Things went well and I particularly enjoyed my 18 mile loop from the train station in Cork out to Ballincollig and back. It beats running 3 times around Bandon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Clon Half was re-scheduled for February and that was as tough as ever, with the added feature of horizontal driving rain. A terribly slow time but it was fine overall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then on to Manchester with 3 of us heading over. The race itself was very flat but also suburban boring. I found it tough mentally but physically I was fine and I did a sprint finish. The non-alcoholic Erdinger at the finish line was a lovely touch. The multi-hour disaster of bag pickup didn&amp;rsquo;t affect me but left a sour taste in everyone&amp;rsquo;s mouths. The fact that I could walk up stairs that evening told me I really hadn&amp;rsquo;t pushed it at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having done the Cork Half a few years ago, it seemed ridiculous that we hadn&amp;rsquo;t done the full &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.corkcitymarathon.ie/&#34;&gt;Cork Marathon&lt;/a&gt;. So we then signed up to run that in June. A few weeks into training and again it was time for the long run. And again the thought of 3 times around Bandon filled us with dread. So, what the hell, we decided to do the &lt;a href=&#34;http://killarneymarathonofthelakes.com/&#34;&gt;Lakes Of Killarney Marathon&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a small event with 3 loops of the National Park. The views were incredible. The day was boiling hot. I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel great. The first loop was OK but up/down hard. Mentally I was in a baddddd place. Half way round the second loop I decided I was going to quit. So I kept going to the checkpoint, crossed the timing mat and started heading towards the barriers to leave. And then, the tannoy boomed &amp;ldquo;And here&amp;rsquo;s Conor O&amp;rsquo;Neill, about to start his third loop.&amp;rdquo;. Nooooooooooo. The only force more effective than exhaustion is shame and embarrassment for an Irish person. So I kept going for another 9 miles. Pure bloody torture. I finished 3rd last. And as always, the moment I crossed the finish line I thought &amp;ldquo;ah that was fine really&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we get to Cork. The third marathon in 8 weeks. What the hell are we at? I thought I&amp;rsquo;d only ever do one marathon! But I was feeling good. The cumulative effect of the training seemed to be helping. No injuries. 1.5 stone lighter than Jan 1st. But still crazily overweight. The race kicked off on Patrick Street. Within a few minutes, my friend Walter appeared and we had a good natter out towards Blackpool and then on towards the tunnel. But, despite his injury, there is no way he could run as slowly as me, so he headed off into the distance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been experimenting with audio for runs. On short ones, I use nothing. For long ones, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using podcasts for many years. Often running podcasts too, to be very meta. But I&amp;rsquo;ve come to the conclusion that [a] I run slower when they are playing and [b] I find it hard to concentrate and overcome pain/tiredness/etc when they are playing. So for Cork I listened to a random &amp;ldquo;dance workout mix&amp;rdquo;. And it bloody worked. Despite physically finding Cork gruelling, I was in a great place mentally for the entire thing. But the hills, jesus how did I forget the relentless goddammed hills? As expected, Model Farm was the absolute nadir. My feet barely moved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sidebar: I&amp;rsquo;ve been on various running forums and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/running/&#34;&gt;/r/running&lt;/a&gt; on Reddit recently and I listen to quite a few running/ultra podcasts. And I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed a tendency for some people there to belittle very slow runners or runner/walkers. My guess is that these are mostly people in their 20s/early-30s at peak fitness who have yet to learn the real meaning of the word empathy. As their bodies age, they may start to understand. During the Cork Marathon, I passed a woman going even slower than me up Model Farm Road. As I approached, I realised from her back-bib that she was running the Half. Yes, this woman was on hour five of a Half Marathon. That&amp;rsquo;s gumption. That&amp;rsquo;s depth of character. That&amp;rsquo;s someone to look up to, rather than snarking about their age/weight/training. So the next time you see someone shuffling slowly along in their runners, do what someone did to me today as I jogged towards the &lt;a href=&#34;http://explorewestcork.ie/walking/seven-heads-walk/&#34;&gt;Fuschia Trail on Seven Heads&lt;/a&gt;. Shout &amp;ldquo;Fair play to you&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finished Cork completely drained. That&amp;rsquo;s the shakiest I&amp;rsquo;ve ever been at the end of my six Marathons. I think it was the heat and possibly screwing up hydration. It took me over a week to feel in any way right. 10 days before I even got on the treadmill. 3 marathons in 8 weeks was maybe a bit much for someone this heavy. But I&amp;rsquo;m so glad I did them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last three small runs were all in the past two weeks. I was in San Francisco at Red Hat Summit and did a 7 mile loop from Crissy Fields over the Golden Gate and back. Loved every minute of it and had perfect weather to take amazing photos. Then we had the Red Hat 5K Fun Run from Moscone to Embarcadero and back. I think that gave me a 5K PB, despite all the traffic lights! And then finally today I ran from Timoleague to Courtmacsherry and round the first short loop of the Seven Heads and back to Timoleague. I can&amp;rsquo;t recommend this route highly enough. You don&amp;rsquo;t need trail runners for the Seven Heads piece but it is hard on the ankles. The plan is to try some of the longer loops soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So next up? Well we&amp;rsquo;re booked for Berlin and that&amp;rsquo;s going to be a PB for me if it kills me. I think we have to do Dublin too, given the year that&amp;rsquo;s in it. But to break up the training boredom we&amp;rsquo;ll probably do a Full and a Half in August. All recommendations welcome. Not too far from Cork tho. Finally, I&amp;rsquo;ll probably just do the Half in Clon in December.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the planning has begun for an Ultra. Hopefully 2017. Hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll be 50lbs lighter. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably start with a 50K to dip the toe in and then I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll be leading the pack at &lt;a href=&#34;http://utmbmontblanc.com/en/&#34;&gt;UTMB&lt;/a&gt; in 2018 ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support KildareStreet.com if you care about democracy</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.com/2015/11/08/support-kildarestreet-com-if-you-care-about-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2015 19:32:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.com/2015/11/08/support-kildarestreet-com-if-you-care-about-democracy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most people in this country seem happy enough to have it run by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rte.ie/news/2011/1102/308186-finance/&#34;&gt;imbeciles&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.moriarty-tribunal.ie/&#34;&gt;criminals&lt;/a&gt;, so it’s a relief that some people actually care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oireachtas.ie/parliament/&#34;&gt;official web-site&lt;/a&gt; which holds the records of the Oireachtas is the kind of incompetent mess that can only have been designed to be that way on purpose. Luckily John Handelaar built &lt;a href=&#34;http://KildareStreet.com&#34;&gt;KildareStreet.com&lt;/a&gt; a few years ago to shine a light on the goings-on in the Dáil and Seanad. Not only does it contain all of the records but it lets you request things like “email me when the clown I voted for actually speaks in the Dáil”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.kildarestreet.com/images/kildarestreetcom.gif&#34; alt=&#34;KildareStreet&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sir Humphrey and his minions made a concerted effort to kill KildareStreet a while back by changing all of their data formats, but they underestimated Mr Handelaar and it is still going strong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might not think this is an important resource until the day it’s gone. We live in a country where the insiders rely on a compliant uninformed populus and a complicit media. It’s scary how critical KildareStreet.com is to our inept democracy. A tiny glimmer of hope in this third-world banana republic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But John and Sabrina can’t afford to run this out of &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@sabrinadent/an-open-letter-to-stephanie-lord-who-is-gutted-about-kildarestreet-com-22a37aaaf148&#34;&gt;the goodness of their hearts&lt;/a&gt;. So go now to &lt;a href=&#34;https://donorbox.org/kildarestreet&#34;&gt;donorbox.org&lt;/a&gt; and vote with your wallet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;ve finally found a running audio setup that works</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.com/2015/10/04/i-ve-finally-found-a-running-audio-setup-that-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 14:02:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.com/2015/10/04/i-ve-finally-found-a-running-audio-setup-that-works/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been running slowly since 2009. This year has seen two and a half marathons so far, with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://runclon.ie/&#34;&gt;Clon Half&lt;/a&gt; probably ending the year nicely. But since the very first run I&amp;rsquo;ve struggled with audio. I think most people listen to music and I&amp;rsquo;ve done that a bit but I&amp;rsquo;ve spent far more time listening to Podcasts. I listened to Kermode and Mayo on my first Half Marathon in Dingle in 2010 and I listened to them again a few weeks ago in Dingle in the 2015 Half.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is when you&amp;rsquo;re in the middle of a podcast and either you find it boring or it annoys you so much you have to turn it off. Some of the more &amp;ldquo;worthy&amp;rdquo; American ones are very hit and miss. As my phone is normally strapped to my arm with a headphone lead snaking down my sleeve, the only thing I can really do is leave the podcast running and pull out the earbuds from my ears. Actually I normally only run with one earbud in for safety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve tried over-ear Bluetooth headphones as a solution but, as a glasses wearer, they give me a headache.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also tried expensive in-ear ones with inline audio controls. But Samsung, in its brilliance, doesn&amp;rsquo;t support them on the S6, apart from play/pause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sidebar: Google and Apple, get into a room, agree a standard one-wire low power digital protocol for audio and bloody implement it. For the love of god.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past I&amp;rsquo;d tried some cheap Chinese Bluetooth adapters too but they were useless and fiddly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then two weeks ago, I discovered that Sony released a pair of ear buds with a Bluetooth audio adapter ages ago, and the reviews were all positive. The official name is Sony SBH20 Stereo Bluetooth Wireless Headset with NFC and Multi-Point Connectivity. Even better, because it&amp;rsquo;s getting-on a bit, the price is now really low. I got mine on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.7dayshop.com/products/sony-sbh20-stereo-bluetooth-wireless-headset-with-nfc-and-multi-point-connectivity-black-WH2-SBH20BK&#34;&gt;7dayshop.com&lt;/a&gt; for £15 delivered!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/sbh20bk-01_1_small.png&#34; alt=&#34;Sony SBH20&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I assumed I&amp;rsquo;d switch the Sony earbuds for something better but they have proven to be perfect for podcasts. They also have very short leads, so you can clip the adapter to the neck of your running top, stick one bud in one ear, loop around your neck and stick the other bud in the other ear. Nothing is left to flap around. It gives you play/pause, prev/next and vol up/down. Works perfectly in BeyondPod on Android. I assume it&amp;rsquo;d be the same on iPhone. After two runs with them, I&amp;rsquo;m completely sold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My next job is to get the podcasts and music visible in one app and build a mixed playlist for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://runclon.ie/half-marathon/&#34;&gt;Clon Half&lt;/a&gt;. Something like Rocky definitely needed for that last hill.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>