<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vegan on Conor&#39;s Bandon Blog</title>
    <link>https://conoroneill.com/categories/vegan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vegan on Conor&#39;s Bandon Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 06:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://conoroneill.com/categories/vegan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mirch Masala - Best vegan menu in Ireland?</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2022/01/26/mirch-masala-best-vegan-menu-in-ireland/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2022/01/26/mirch-masala-best-vegan-menu-in-ireland/</guid>
      <description>We are spending two weeks in Clon whilst our kitchen gets rebuilt and decided to treat ourselves to an Indian takeaway on the first night. A bit of googling revealed that there was a new place called Mirch Masala, so I loaded up their website on my phone and my jaw hit the floor as I started browsing the menu.
The range of vegan and vegetarian options is almost beyond belief.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Flahavan&#39;s Oat Milk can out-market the big brands</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2021/10/17/how-flahavans-oat-milk-can-outmarket-the-big-brands/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2021/10/17/how-flahavans-oat-milk-can-outmarket-the-big-brands/</guid>
      <description>I was so pleased when I heard Flahavan&amp;rsquo;s was getting into the oat milk market. As the most famous porridge brand in Ireland, it seemed like an obvious move.
 I only turned plant-based in January 2020 and switched to oat milk pretty quickly as I preferred, and still prefer, its taste to all the other plant milks. Having Flahavans as an option along with the usual Oatly, Califia, Minor Figures and Alpro means I can now finally support Irish farmers again with my cuppa tea and coffee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Irish Lockdown Vegan Brown Soda Bread recipe</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2020/06/19/irish-lockdown-vegan-brown-bread-recipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 06:17:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2020/06/19/irish-lockdown-vegan-brown-bread-recipe/</guid>
      <description>In January 2020, I went 99.9% plant-based as a way of kick-starting serious weight loss after 20 years of being either overweight or obese. The only initial exception was cow milk in my tea. I did similar back in 2016 but that was my silly &amp;ldquo;6 Day Vegan&amp;rdquo; plan where I ate chicken curry on a Friday. Both times I&amp;rsquo;ve used Veganuary as the starting point.
After two months at 99.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
