<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reviews on Conor&#39;s Bandon Blog</title>
    <link>https://conoroneill.com/categories/reviews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reviews on Conor&#39;s Bandon Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 11:00:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://conoroneill.com/categories/reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>La Sportiva Prodigio Max is a big disappointment - Running Shoe Review</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2025/12/31/la-sportiva-prodigio-max-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 11:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2025/12/31/la-sportiva-prodigio-max-review/</guid>
      <description>As I have only done 30km in the La Sportiva Prodigio Max so far, you can take this review with a grain of salt. You can read my full review of the La Sportiva Prodigio Pro here, which I absolutely loved. So when the Max was announced I immediately pounced. I was imagining something like the Pro but for massive distances. Possible a wider base and toe-box with a more cushioned relaxed ride.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>La Sportiva Prodigio Pro is the new King of the Mountains - Running Shoe Review</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2025/07/28/la-sportiva-prodigio-pro-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 05:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2025/07/28/la-sportiva-prodigio-pro-review/</guid>
      <description>This won&amp;rsquo;t be a very long review as there&amp;rsquo;s not a lot to say about the La Sportiva Prodigio Pro, other than go buy them now!
I&amp;rsquo;ve spent the past few years mostly running in the Hoka Speedgoat and the Brooks Caldera. If you&amp;rsquo;ve read my other reviews you&amp;rsquo;ll know that I also like the NNormal Tomir 2.0 and the Saucony Endorphin Rift. OTOH, I rate the Salomon Vision as the worst trail shoe in decades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hoka Speedgoat 5 Mid GTX boots are life savers - Running Shoe Review</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2024/09/07/hoka-speedgoat-5-mid-gtx-boots-are-life-savers-running-shoe-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 07:01:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2024/09/07/hoka-speedgoat-5-mid-gtx-boots-are-life-savers-running-shoe-review/</guid>
      <description>As you can read in my review of the truly awful Salomon Vision shoes, my hopes of running the Kerry Way Ultra in 2024 were ruined last weekend. I had an x-ray on Monday to confirm that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a break.
I then went to my physio/PT on Tuesday. He confirmed multile ligament tears. He was pretty blunt that I&amp;rsquo;d be nuts to try KWU. Despite all the icing, compression and elevation that I had done since Saturday, I still had very restricted motion and some pain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The DOA Salomon Vision is another ankle breaker - Running Shoe Review</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2024/09/01/salomon-vision-review-is-another-ankle-breaker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 13:01:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2024/09/01/salomon-vision-review-is-another-ankle-breaker/</guid>
      <description>This won&amp;rsquo;t be a long review. How could it be when I&amp;rsquo;ve only done 1 km in the Salomon Vision. It&amp;rsquo;s more of a rant.
I buy maybe 6-7 pairs of running shoes a year. Usually equally split between road and trail. For many years the trail ones were Altra, Hoka, Inov-8 and Brooks. I wanted to try Salomon but every review made it sound like I&amp;rsquo;d have to remove two toes to fit into them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The NNormal Tomir 2.0 is a grower - Running Shoe Review</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2024/09/01/nnormal-tomir-20-review-a-grower/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 07:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2024/09/01/nnormal-tomir-20-review-a-grower/</guid>
      <description>I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine there&amp;rsquo;s a trail runner alive who hasn&amp;rsquo;t heard of Kilian Jornet. He&amp;rsquo;s the goat when it comes to mountains. 6 years ago my kids brilliantly reached out to him and John Kelly to see if they could get an autograph or something to mark my 50th birthday. Kilian sent a very cool signed card and John, the legend, sent me a video, which I&amp;rsquo;ll never forget.
So the whole NNormal thing obviously caught my attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is the Saucony Endorphin Rift my new do-anything trail shoe?</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2024/03/18/is-the-saucony-endorphin-rift-my-new-do-anything-trail-shoe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 10:17:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2024/03/18/is-the-saucony-endorphin-rift-my-new-do-anything-trail-shoe/</guid>
      <description>I have a strange relationship with Saucony running shoes. The Endorphin Speed was the first time I&amp;rsquo;d bought any shoe from them and it instantly became my favourite road shoe of all time. V2 was equally good. My Endorphin Pro 1, whilst flawed, has more miles on it than any other pair of shoes I still have in rotation.
And then there are their trail shoes which have been an unmitigated disaster for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Brooks Caldera 7 is a step backwards from the 6</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2024/03/18/the-brooks-caldera-7-is-a-step-backwards-from-the-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 09:17:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2024/03/18/the-brooks-caldera-7-is-a-step-backwards-from-the-6/</guid>
      <description>I did most of my trail running over the past year in 2 pairs of Brooks Caldera 6. They did sterling work in my three Ultra DNFs and many training miles. Strangely I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve seen a single other runner wearing them.
I gave them a very positive review last year which I updated when I realised they had one terrible design flaw - the two parts of the upper separated during a run because they were only connected via a thin layer of glue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Brooks Caldera 6 is an ultra-devouring monster (but)</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2023/05/22/the-brooks-caldera-6-is-an-ultra-devouring-monster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2023/05/22/the-brooks-caldera-6-is-an-ultra-devouring-monster/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: See below for a major proviso to this post.
My entire history with Brooks until a few months ago was one pair of Adrenaline 19s which did not suit me at all. I always associated the brand with big reliable heavy running shoes for conservative joggers. The Caldera 6 takes that reputation and shreds it, in the best possible sense.
 The perfect shoe doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist I&amp;rsquo;ve been on the hunt for the ultimate ultra-distance trail running shoe since I started going longer in 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
