<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conor&#39;s Bandon Blog</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Conor&#39;s Bandon Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 19:32:32 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.com/atom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Seven Heads Walk, Fuschia Walk and Lusitania Trail is one of West Cork&#39;s best kept secrets. Just go.</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.com/2016/08/26/the-seven-heads-walk-and-lusitania-trail-is-one-of-west-corks-best-kept-secrets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 19:32:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.com/2016/08/26/the-seven-heads-walk-and-lusitania-trail-is-one-of-west-corks-best-kept-secrets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shortly after we moved to Bandon, over 10 years ago, I bought a bunch of Ordnance Survey maps of the area and two books by Damien Enright called &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Walks-Courtmacsherry-Seven-Damien-Enright/dp/1902631005&#34;&gt;Walks of Courtmacsherry Bay &amp;amp; The Seven Heads&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Walks in and around Kinsale&amp;rdquo;. We had high hopes of being outdoorsy. To our shame, the most we ever did was to haul the kids along the short track in Kilbrittain woods, the even shorter one in Ballinspittle woods and the tiny bit longer one in Dromillihy woods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lack of places to safely walk in West Cork outside of towns is ridiculous. I have a separate monster blogpost coming that includes this topic. It&amp;rsquo;s a cracker. But this one is about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sevenheadspeninsula.ie/&#34;&gt;The Seven Heads&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/3QOn-AdXV_s&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve recently become very interested in the whole idea of trail running. By interested I mean I watch huge numbers of YouTube videos about it and revel in the incredible achievements of people who do races like &lt;a href=&#34;http://barkleymovie.com/&#34;&gt;The Barkley Marathons&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://utmbmontblanc.com/en/&#34;&gt;UTMB (Ultra Trail de Mont Blanc)&lt;/a&gt; which started two hours ago. But a few weeks ago I finally decided I wanted to make some sort of attempt at doing it myself. Of course I had to do a pre-run, so I hauled the smaller kids out to Courtmac and the start of what now seems to be more formally called The Lusitania Trail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I did when dragged on walks by my parents, they hated every step. I loved every minute. The route was basically the first recommended short loop. You can read all the details over on the superb pages on &lt;a href=&#34;http://explorewestcork.ie/walking/seven-heads-walk/&#34;&gt;Explore West Cork&lt;/a&gt;. In fact I printed out their directions and made a copy of that section of Map 87. In reality you need none of that, since the whole thing is now signposted as The Lusitania Trail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the ever-changing views that make this such a spectacular walk. You begin in Courtmac, then into woods with beautiful little slipways down to the water, then suddenly the first gobsmacking headland and the Atlantic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty easy walk apart from places where the cows have mushed the ground up badly. Lots of stiles separate the fields and it&amp;rsquo;s completely safe. The Fuschia Walk is absolutely beautiful and you come back through the lovely Ramsey Hill cottages and then on footpath all the way to Courtmac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-08-07%2010.54.36.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Leaving Woods&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-08-07%2010.54.50.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;First Look&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was so delighted with our trip that I vowed to come back. A few weeks passed and I repeated the route but started in Timoleague and ran most of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-08-07%2010.04.42.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Timoleague&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was tough on the ankles in places but the weather was fantastic so I didn&amp;rsquo;t need trail runners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-08-07%2010.54.54.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ankles&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two weeks later I was back again. This time it was a 15 mile loop that again started in Timoleague. I found that the written directions on Explore West Cork were very hard to follow and I did a lot of recce via Google Maps and the Ordnance Survey map in advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-08-07%2011.06.28.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Woods&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-08-07%2011.06.54.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Woods2&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, yet again, the entire route was signposted and took almost no thinking on my part. The only place I got confused was on Broadstrand where you have to go the entire length of the beach before you see the steps back up to the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-08-07%2011.27.55.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Meelmane&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-08-07%2011.31.20.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Broadstrand&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-08-07%2011.43.00.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Statue&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is one very steep path up along some fields and then an old pre-Famine road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-08-07 11.52.16.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Start famine Road&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which eventually brings you out to this amazing view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-08-07%2012.09.01.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Headlands&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got to Narry&amp;rsquo;s Cross and then I returned along some very quiet roads via Lislee and a busy main road back into Courtmacsherry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-08-07%2012.42.17.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lislee&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-08-07%2012.52.43.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Main Road&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to take a breather there and have an ice-cream and Lucozade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/2016-08-07%2013.13.27.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ice Cream&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then the final push back to the car in Timoleague.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I fully intend to go again soon and run the entire route which is heading towards Ultra Marathon length. Well, when I say run, I mean run-walk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason I wanted to write this post is that the Seven Heads walk is little more than a name for many people. It&amp;rsquo;s barely a 20 minute drive from Bandon. Probably less from Clonakilty. Much of it is completely off-road with no asshole drivers. If you are looking for some of the best views in the country and a bit of exercise, you owe it to yourself to check it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep an eye out for my next post which takes this basic topic and turns it into a very long rant about the future of the country&amp;rsquo;s health.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A year of running updates</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.com/2016/07/10/a-year-of-running-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2016 18:32:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.com/2016/07/10/a-year-of-running-updates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As has been the case so often over the past 15 years of blogging, I&amp;rsquo;ve been very remiss in my updates. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a ton of things I want to write about, like the Waterford Greenway and how adventure/outdoor tourism could be a much bigger business here. But that&amp;rsquo;s for my holidays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, as I move this blog to &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/]&#34;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; (what a journey it has had!), I thought I&amp;rsquo;d just give an update on my running. The last time I mentioned it, I had &lt;a href=&#34;http://conoroneill.com/2015/05/03/this-heavy-guy-decided-to-run-the-london-marathon-and-you-won-t-believe-what-happened-next/&#34;&gt;just finished the London Marathon&lt;/a&gt;. Still a life highlight for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of 2015 was quiet from a &amp;ldquo;race&amp;rdquo; perspective. I signed up for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dinglemarathon.ie/&#34;&gt;Dingle Marathon&lt;/a&gt; and then chickened out and did the Half. Very glad I did, as I&amp;rsquo;d forgotten what a tough course it is. But it is still one of the greatest routes anywhere on the planet. Even the Top Gear guys agree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://runclon.ie/&#34;&gt;Clon Half&lt;/a&gt; was delayed due to the flooding, so basically I spent most of 2015 doing short runs around the town and on the treadmill and making no impact on my weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So January 1st lands and we decide to really push it. We signed up for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.greatermanchestermarathon.com/&#34;&gt;Greater Manchester Marathon&lt;/a&gt; in April and kicked off training. Things went well and I particularly enjoyed my 18 mile loop from the train station in Cork out to Ballincollig and back. It beats running 3 times around Bandon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Clon Half was re-scheduled for February and that was as tough as ever, with the added feature of horizontal driving rain. A terribly slow time but it was fine overall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then on to Manchester with 3 of us heading over. The race itself was very flat but also suburban boring. I found it tough mentally but physically I was fine and I did a sprint finish. The non-alcoholic Erdinger at the finish line was a lovely touch. The multi-hour disaster of bag pickup didn&amp;rsquo;t affect me but left a sour taste in everyone&amp;rsquo;s mouths. The fact that I could walk up stairs that evening told me I really hadn&amp;rsquo;t pushed it at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having done the Cork Half a few years ago, it seemed ridiculous that we hadn&amp;rsquo;t done the full &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.corkcitymarathon.ie/&#34;&gt;Cork Marathon&lt;/a&gt;. So we then signed up to run that in June. A few weeks into training and again it was time for the long run. And again the thought of 3 times around Bandon filled us with dread. So, what the hell, we decided to do the &lt;a href=&#34;http://killarneymarathonofthelakes.com/&#34;&gt;Lakes Of Killarney Marathon&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a small event with 3 loops of the National Park. The views were incredible. The day was boiling hot. I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel great. The first loop was OK but up/down hard. Mentally I was in a baddddd place. Half way round the second loop I decided I was going to quit. So I kept going to the checkpoint, crossed the timing mat and started heading towards the barriers to leave. And then, the tannoy boomed &amp;ldquo;And here&amp;rsquo;s Conor O&amp;rsquo;Neill, about to start his third loop.&amp;rdquo;. Nooooooooooo. The only force more effective than exhaustion is shame and embarrassment for an Irish person. So I kept going for another 9 miles. Pure bloody torture. I finished 3rd last. And as always, the moment I crossed the finish line I thought &amp;ldquo;ah that was fine really&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we get to Cork. The third marathon in 8 weeks. What the hell are we at? I thought I&amp;rsquo;d only ever do one marathon! But I was feeling good. The cumulative effect of the training seemed to be helping. No injuries. 1.5 stone lighter than Jan 1st. But still crazily overweight. The race kicked off on Patrick Street. Within a few minutes, my friend Walter appeared and we had a good natter out towards Blackpool and then on towards the tunnel. But, despite his injury, there is no way he could run as slowly as me, so he headed off into the distance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been experimenting with audio for runs. On short ones, I use nothing. For long ones, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using podcasts for many years. Often running podcasts too, to be very meta. But I&amp;rsquo;ve come to the conclusion that [a] I run slower when they are playing and [b] I find it hard to concentrate and overcome pain/tiredness/etc when they are playing. So for Cork I listened to a random &amp;ldquo;dance workout mix&amp;rdquo;. And it bloody worked. Despite physically finding Cork gruelling, I was in a great place mentally for the entire thing. But the hills, jesus how did I forget the relentless goddammed hills? As expected, Model Farm was the absolute nadir. My feet barely moved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sidebar: I&amp;rsquo;ve been on various running forums and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/running/&#34;&gt;/r/running&lt;/a&gt; on Reddit recently and I listen to quite a few running/ultra podcasts. And I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed a tendency for some people there to belittle very slow runners or runner/walkers. My guess is that these are mostly people in their 20s/early-30s at peak fitness who have yet to learn the real meaning of the word empathy. As their bodies age, they may start to understand. During the Cork Marathon, I passed a woman going even slower than me up Model Farm Road. As I approached, I realised from her back-bib that she was running the Half. Yes, this woman was on hour five of a Half Marathon. That&amp;rsquo;s gumption. That&amp;rsquo;s depth of character. That&amp;rsquo;s someone to look up to, rather than snarking about their age/weight/training. So the next time you see someone shuffling slowly along in their runners, do what someone did to me today as I jogged towards the &lt;a href=&#34;http://explorewestcork.ie/walking/seven-heads-walk/&#34;&gt;Fuschia Trail on Seven Heads&lt;/a&gt;. Shout &amp;ldquo;Fair play to you&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finished Cork completely drained. That&amp;rsquo;s the shakiest I&amp;rsquo;ve ever been at the end of my six Marathons. I think it was the heat and possibly screwing up hydration. It took me over a week to feel in any way right. 10 days before I even got on the treadmill. 3 marathons in 8 weeks was maybe a bit much for someone this heavy. But I&amp;rsquo;m so glad I did them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last three small runs were all in the past two weeks. I was in San Francisco at Red Hat Summit and did a 7 mile loop from Crissy Fields over the Golden Gate and back. Loved every minute of it and had perfect weather to take amazing photos. Then we had the Red Hat 5K Fun Run from Moscone to Embarcadero and back. I think that gave me a 5K PB, despite all the traffic lights! And then finally today I ran from Timoleague to Courtmacsherry and round the first short loop of the Seven Heads and back to Timoleague. I can&amp;rsquo;t recommend this route highly enough. You don&amp;rsquo;t need trail runners for the Seven Heads piece but it is hard on the ankles. The plan is to try some of the longer loops soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So next up? Well we&amp;rsquo;re booked for Berlin and that&amp;rsquo;s going to be a PB for me if it kills me. I think we have to do Dublin too, given the year that&amp;rsquo;s in it. But to break up the training boredom we&amp;rsquo;ll probably do a Full and a Half in August. All recommendations welcome. Not too far from Cork tho. Finally, I&amp;rsquo;ll probably just do the Half in Clon in December.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the planning has begun for an Ultra. Hopefully 2017. Hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll be 50lbs lighter. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably start with a 50K to dip the toe in and then I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll be leading the pack at &lt;a href=&#34;http://utmbmontblanc.com/en/&#34;&gt;UTMB&lt;/a&gt; in 2018 ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support KildareStreet.com if you care about democracy</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.com/2015/11/08/support-kildarestreet-com-if-you-care-about-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2015 19:32:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.com/2015/11/08/support-kildarestreet-com-if-you-care-about-democracy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most people in this country seem happy enough to have it run by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rte.ie/news/2011/1102/308186-finance/&#34;&gt;imbeciles&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.moriarty-tribunal.ie/&#34;&gt;criminals&lt;/a&gt;, so it’s a relief that some people actually care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oireachtas.ie/parliament/&#34;&gt;official web-site&lt;/a&gt; which holds the records of the Oireachtas is the kind of incompetent mess that can only have been designed to be that way on purpose. Luckily John Handelaar built &lt;a href=&#34;http://KildareStreet.com&#34;&gt;KildareStreet.com&lt;/a&gt; a few years ago to shine a light on the goings-on in the Dáil and Seanad. Not only does it contain all of the records but it lets you request things like “email me when the clown I voted for actually speaks in the Dáil”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.kildarestreet.com/images/kildarestreetcom.gif&#34; alt=&#34;KildareStreet&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sir Humphrey and his minions made a concerted effort to kill KildareStreet a while back by changing all of their data formats, but they underestimated Mr Handelaar and it is still going strong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might not think this is an important resource until the day it’s gone. We live in a country where the insiders rely on a compliant uninformed populus and a complicit media. It’s scary how critical KildareStreet.com is to our inept democracy. A tiny glimmer of hope in this third-world banana republic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But John and Sabrina can’t afford to run this out of &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@sabrinadent/an-open-letter-to-stephanie-lord-who-is-gutted-about-kildarestreet-com-22a37aaaf148&#34;&gt;the goodness of their hearts&lt;/a&gt;. So go now to &lt;a href=&#34;https://donorbox.org/kildarestreet&#34;&gt;donorbox.org&lt;/a&gt; and vote with your wallet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;ve finally found a running audio setup that works</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.com/2015/10/04/i-ve-finally-found-a-running-audio-setup-that-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 14:02:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.com/2015/10/04/i-ve-finally-found-a-running-audio-setup-that-works/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been running slowly since 2009. This year has seen two and a half marathons so far, with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://runclon.ie/&#34;&gt;Clon Half&lt;/a&gt; probably ending the year nicely. But since the very first run I&amp;rsquo;ve struggled with audio. I think most people listen to music and I&amp;rsquo;ve done that a bit but I&amp;rsquo;ve spent far more time listening to Podcasts. I listened to Kermode and Mayo on my first Half Marathon in Dingle in 2010 and I listened to them again a few weeks ago in Dingle in the 2015 Half.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is when you&amp;rsquo;re in the middle of a podcast and either you find it boring or it annoys you so much you have to turn it off. Some of the more &amp;ldquo;worthy&amp;rdquo; American ones are very hit and miss. As my phone is normally strapped to my arm with a headphone lead snaking down my sleeve, the only thing I can really do is leave the podcast running and pull out the earbuds from my ears. Actually I normally only run with one earbud in for safety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve tried over-ear Bluetooth headphones as a solution but, as a glasses wearer, they give me a headache.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also tried expensive in-ear ones with inline audio controls. But Samsung, in its brilliance, doesn&amp;rsquo;t support them on the S6, apart from play/pause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sidebar: Google and Apple, get into a room, agree a standard one-wire low power digital protocol for audio and bloody implement it. For the love of god.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past I&amp;rsquo;d tried some cheap Chinese Bluetooth adapters too but they were useless and fiddly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then two weeks ago, I discovered that Sony released a pair of ear buds with a Bluetooth audio adapter ages ago, and the reviews were all positive. The official name is Sony SBH20 Stereo Bluetooth Wireless Headset with NFC and Multi-Point Connectivity. Even better, because it&amp;rsquo;s getting-on a bit, the price is now really low. I got mine on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.7dayshop.com/products/sony-sbh20-stereo-bluetooth-wireless-headset-with-nfc-and-multi-point-connectivity-black-WH2-SBH20BK&#34;&gt;7dayshop.com&lt;/a&gt; for £15 delivered!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/sbh20bk-01_1_small.png&#34; alt=&#34;Sony SBH20&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I assumed I&amp;rsquo;d switch the Sony earbuds for something better but they have proven to be perfect for podcasts. They also have very short leads, so you can clip the adapter to the neck of your running top, stick one bud in one ear, loop around your neck and stick the other bud in the other ear. Nothing is left to flap around. It gives you play/pause, prev/next and vol up/down. Works perfectly in BeyondPod on Android. I assume it&amp;rsquo;d be the same on iPhone. After two runs with them, I&amp;rsquo;m completely sold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My next job is to get the podcasts and music visible in one app and build a mixed playlist for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://runclon.ie/half-marathon/&#34;&gt;Clon Half&lt;/a&gt;. Something like Rocky definitely needed for that last hill.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This heavy guy decided to run the London Marathon and you won&#39;t believe what happened next.</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.com/2015/05/03/this-heavy-guy-decided-to-run-the-london-marathon-and-you-won-t-believe-what-happened-next/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2015 19:03:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.com/2015/05/03/this-heavy-guy-decided-to-run-the-london-marathon-and-you-won-t-believe-what-happened-next/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I figured it was either that title or &amp;ldquo;5 ways you can run the London Marathon without even trying&amp;rdquo; ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;d told me in 2008 that I&amp;rsquo;d ever run a 10k, I&amp;rsquo;d have laughed at you. If you&amp;rsquo;d told me in 2009 that I&amp;rsquo;d ever run a half marathon, I&amp;rsquo;d have laughed at you. If you&amp;rsquo;d told me in 2011 that I&amp;rsquo;d ever run a marathon, I&amp;rsquo;d have laughed at you. If you&amp;rsquo;d told me in 2014 that I&amp;rsquo;d ever run two marathons in 5 weeks, I&amp;rsquo;d have laughed at you. You get my point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&#34;http://conoroneill.com/2013/01/02/three-full-years-a-running-and-my-first-marathon/&#34;&gt;blogged two years ago&lt;/a&gt; about the Dublin Marathon and I thought that was the last time I&amp;rsquo;d ever mention a marathon. I&amp;rsquo;ve done several half marathons and 10k runs since but at the back of my mind I wondered if I&amp;rsquo;d ever give 26.2 miles another go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had an abortive attempt at training for Dublin 2014 but then in December my wife suggested we do London. Initially I thought no. If I was ever to do it, I&amp;rsquo;d want to lose 5 stone and be ultra fit so I&amp;rsquo;d do it in a time to be proud of. But I thought about it more and realised I could be dead long before then. As a Carpe Diem kind of person it just made sense to do it. So our Christmas present to each other was entry to the 2015 London Marathon (via the absolutely superb &lt;a href=&#34;http://sportstravelinternational.com/&#34;&gt;Sports Travel International&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Training went well as I lost 1.5 stone, upped my speeds and experimented with various minimal-drop non-Five-Fingers running shoes. Then we realised in early March that some travel and Easter would mess up the training schedule. I was following the London Intermediate schedule which meant that 22 miles was the peak training distance but I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be around to do that weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we decided to throw caution to the wind and do the Tralee Marathon for &amp;ldquo;practice&amp;rdquo;. One reason I was a big fan of this idea was that I could make all the mistakes and deal with all the worry in Tralee. It was a very small race of fewer than 400 people and I came 8th last in a time of 5:45. Most of the slowness was caused by my walking up the hills of the second half. But I was happy because it was very doable, I didn&amp;rsquo;t destroy my body and I didn&amp;rsquo;t lose my mind!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now London felt totally manageable and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t stressed at all. I upped my speed some more in the final weeks to see if I could crack 5 hours in London. I gave up on using the New Balance MR00 and I could not get comfortable in a new pair of MR10 so my old knackered worn-heel pair of MR10 were chosen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally the day came. A 6am wake-up and we arrived at the start area by coach with over two hours to wait. The crowds of runners just built and built. The announcer said that 38000 people were due to start. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t even imagine how many people that is! The adrenalin began to flow and the wind, drizzle and cool temperature did nothing to reduce my enthusiasm. Hot tea and coffee was an unusual but much appreciated aid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 10am I shed my Christmas jumper and lined up the podcasts on my phone. Catherine headed to the faster zone and I went to the rear. At 10:10 I started RunKeeper and the shuffle to the start line began. As soon as we crossed the line, I began running and had none of the predicted start-stop that London is infamous for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/conor_marathon_start.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Marathon Start Line&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next 5 hours and 40 minutes were like nothing I&amp;rsquo;ve ever experienced in my life. I&amp;rsquo;m going to struggle to describe just how it felt. If you&amp;rsquo;ve heard that the crowds in London are great then you still haven&amp;rsquo;t the vaguest idea of what the people of London do for the Marathon. It&amp;rsquo;s on an epic scale. Imagine 26.2 miles of people all lined up on both sides of the roads winding through London all cheering shouting, banging, singing, playing and dancing. And all of that energy is targeted at you. Non stop. It&amp;rsquo;s a completely transcendent experience. At times I felt like I wasn&amp;rsquo;t running and they were just carrying my sore legs along. I came close to tears on Tower Bridge with the location and the &amp;ldquo;moment&amp;rdquo;. I nearly lost it completely at mile 23 with the emotional impact of all the crowds and the music and the pain and the encouragement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know London well, I&amp;rsquo;ve never worked there. My semi-regular visits have never really given me a feeling for the place. On Sunday I think I saw the real London. I saw the soul of an amazing city. Where every area from the poorest to the richest was loudly willing you to succeed. Where everyone from the most ultra athlete to overweight people blobs like me were given the same encouragement and love from hundreds of thousands of people for 6 hours plus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crossing that line is a life moment that&amp;rsquo;s now burned into my mind forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/conor_marathon_finish_line.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Marathon Finish Line&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve run races in Amsterdam, Cork, Dublin, Galway, Kerry and Wexford. I&amp;rsquo;ve watched my wife run more in Paris and Rome. None of them, none, come even close to what happened on the streets of London. My time is irrelevant, you can&amp;rsquo;t measure the effect that day had on me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I now finally know why many people rate it as the greatest of all the major marathons. It&amp;rsquo;s got nothing to do with the route. It&amp;rsquo;s taking part in an incredible experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/conor_marathon_end.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Marathon End&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t need a bucket list. I&amp;rsquo;ve done London. Thank you Londoners.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So long WordPress. Hello Hexo.</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.com/2015/03/05/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2015 08:48:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.com/2015/03/05/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been blogging longer than the average bear, with my first post wayyyy back in 2001 on Blogger. I moved to WordPress in 2005 and did a huge amount of stuff with it both personally and professionally until 2013.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, like many people, I&amp;rsquo;ve had it with WordPress. Pretty much every WP blog I either ran or had some dealings with, has been hacked. Whether through security-hole-riddled plugins, xmlrpc.php or other bugs in WP. I just don&amp;rsquo;t have the time to constantly update eveything and hope it&amp;rsquo;s alright. The botnets relentlessly trying to login to all of the blogs and managing to mini-DDoS me on a regular basis are just the pooh on the cake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So over the past 2 years I&amp;rsquo;ve moved most of my blogs and sites to static setups. Good old HTML, CSS and JS without a whiff of PHP or MySQL. This has been a huge success for me and I simply don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about any of those sites. I&amp;rsquo;ve popped the images up on S3 for performance too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My tool of choice for all of this has been &lt;a href=&#34;http://harpjs.com/&#34;&gt;Harp&lt;/a&gt; and I&amp;rsquo;ve been happy with it apart from the very long generation time with each new post on &lt;a href=&#34;http://conoroneill.net&#34;&gt;conoroneill.net&lt;/a&gt;. Basically it re-generates the entire site for every new post/page. And with close to 1000 posts there, that takes 5+ minutes even on an 8-core machine (presumably because it&amp;rsquo;s doing them all sequentially).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when it came time to kill my last install of WordPress here on conoroneill.com, I decided to see what else was out there in the &amp;ldquo;Node.js Static Site Generation Tool&amp;rdquo; world. And I quickly found &lt;a href=&#34;http://hexo.io/&#34;&gt;Hexo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/hexo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Hexo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hexo is a fairly new static blogging platform from Taiwan that seems to have built a community very quickly. It is very easy to use/setup and has import tools for the usual suspects including WordPress. The latter had a one-line bug which I fixed and they have merged already. Getting all of the old posts from WordPress involved taking the export file from WP and running it through the Hexo migration tool a few times and making some fixes. It found a few problems like dodgy markup from old WP plugins and a crazy number of categories/tags. A bit ot search/replace fixing in Notepad++ sorted that out and I got a clean import working with very little effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love how quickly it generates static pages and the general ease of use and configuration but obviously you have to be comfortable using Command Line tools and editing Markdown if you want to use it. However, if you are sick of the WP treadmill, it may be a solution for you too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Please someone make a documentary on TB hospitals in Ireland</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.com/2014/02/01/please-someone-make-a-documentary-on-tb-hospitals-in-ireland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 18:41:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.com/2014/02/01/please-someone-make-a-documentary-on-tb-hospitals-in-ireland/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Four years ago I wrote &lt;a href=&#34;http://conoroneill.com/2009/01/17/tb-hospitals-in-ireland/&#34;&gt;a quick throwaway post&lt;/a&gt; about TB hospitals in Ireland. For whatever reason it bubbles up very close to the top of any google search on that topic. As a result, I have set of comments there which just have to be read. All of them are interesting, many are heartbreaking. The majority are written by people who were either in such a hospital or had a relation in one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.peamount.ie&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/the-administration-building-circa-1913.png&#34; alt=&#34;the-administration-building-circa-1913&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I implore someone to take this information and do a proper documentary on it before it&amp;rsquo;s too late and all of these people are gone. These stories have been hidden for far too long, just like so many other parts of our 20th century history in Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is anyone out there up to the task?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two lovely hot sauces from Mexico</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.com/2014/01/01/two-lovely-hot-sauces-from-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 17:21:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.com/2014/01/01/two-lovely-hot-sauces-from-mexico/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a while, I know. I spent most of 2013 focused on &lt;a href=&#34;http://conoroneill.net/&#34;&gt;my tech blog over here&lt;/a&gt;. But I thought I&amp;rsquo;d kick off 2014 with a foodie post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use a lot of hot sauce but tend to be very boring in the ones I buy, mainly sticking to the supermarket reliables like Tabasco and Encona. I&amp;rsquo;ve got the odd Irish one too but many of them seem obsessed with heat and not flavour (Rebel Chilli being the worst culprit here).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my &lt;a href=&#34;http://conoroneill.com/2006/03/31/buffalo-wings-mmm-tasty-but-not-so-hot/&#34;&gt;most spammed blogposts here&lt;/a&gt; is the one I did on Frank&amp;rsquo;s Hot Sauce back in 2006. However I&amp;rsquo;ve long given up on Franks due to the lack of kick and depth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently &lt;a href=&#34;http://qz.com/132738/the-highly-unusual-company-behind-siracha-the-worlds-coolest-hot-sauce/&#34;&gt;read an article about the Sriracha&lt;/a&gt; obsession in the US. It lead me to believe that only one company in California was responsible for it and the distinct bottle. But their company name bears no resemblance to the one in my fridge, so I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how accurate anything they said was. I only use Sriracha in kebabs (I know, culture clash) as I find it a bit a too raw-garlic-smelly. Then I found &lt;a href=&#34;http://pando.com/2013/12/12/lets-face-it-sriracha-isnt-that-good/&#34;&gt;this great piece on Pando daily&lt;/a&gt;, giving Sriracha a good kicking and recommending some alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ones he mentioned that stood out for me were by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.elyucateco.com/&#34;&gt;El Yucateco&lt;/a&gt; and I found a bunch of places online selling them without too big a gouge to Ireland. So I ordered their Chipotle Hot Sauce and Green Chile Habanero Hot Sauce &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ebay.co.uk/itm/El-Yucateco-Chipotle-Hot-Sauce-/131057906997?ssPageName=ADME:L:OU:IE:3160&#34;&gt;off eBay&lt;/a&gt;.  And boy am I glad I did. The Chipotle is a bit too smokey straight out of the bottle on to your finger, but it does some sort of crazy transformation the second it hits food. Everything tastes better, everything! It must be packed with umami. It&amp;rsquo;s not very hot but adds depth and some heat to spruce up even the most boring of foods. The Habanero is very hot, but not madly so. It is lovely and fresh and adds a lot of zing. A great replacement for Tabasco or Encona everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/2013-12-22-13.52.52.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/2013-12-22-13.52.52.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;2013-12-22 13.52.52&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try them out. I&amp;rsquo;ll be ordering more soon as I&amp;rsquo;m nearly out already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poacher&#39;s Inn Tapas Night. Staggeringly good. Epic in fact.</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.com/2013/03/03/poachers-inn-tapas-night-staggeringly-good-epic-in-fact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 12:51:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.com/2013/03/03/poachers-inn-tapas-night-staggeringly-good-epic-in-fact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For a good few years, this blog was all about food. I had lots of restaurant reviews and foodie pics and experiments like making sausages. Unfortunately, for a variety of reasons, I haven&amp;rsquo;t done much in that area for a long time. Whilst I&amp;rsquo;ve eaten lots of lovely food since then, I haven&amp;rsquo;t had much that was truly memorable. Until Friday night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My parents were down for a visit and we planned to go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/poachersinnbandon&#34;&gt;The Poacher&amp;rsquo;s Inn&lt;/a&gt; with them and big sis, but when we went to book we were told the Tapas night was starting at 8pm and it was only a very limited menu before that. As we hate to eat late, we decided to go to Bandon&amp;rsquo;s other superb restaurant, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chapelsteps.ie/&#34;&gt;Chapel Steps&lt;/a&gt;. We figured it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be too busy around 6.30pm and we didn&amp;rsquo;t bother book a table. Boy were we wrong. They were jammed and didn&amp;rsquo;t have a table free when we arrived. Whilst it was a disappointment for us, I was thrilled for Siobhan and the team. They&amp;rsquo;ve got an absolute winner on their hands now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So back to Poacher&amp;rsquo;s and not only did they have a table, they were happy to give us the Tapas menu early. I was chuffed! We ordered a clatter of plates for sharing. We knew we had to be out by 8pm and were relieved when the plates started coming thick and fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not a single dud. Not one. Everything was gorgeous and lots of it was surprising. The tempura oysters with pepper sauce were a revelation. The sauce on the whole prawns was completely addictive. I could go on and on about the tastes but I think a few pictures are called for. Apologies for the rubbish picture quality. It was quite dark and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find the option to turn on the flash as a light in the camera app on the phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Superb olives:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-WXXLWcHPyxI/UTD7IJ3cJ2I/AAAAAAAAkq8/CV0fPT7ytHk/s641/IMG_20130301_190035.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Local cheeses and meats (that pickled cauliflower was a thing of joy):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-vLEHN2PX-Qs/UTD6-pvpD9I/AAAAAAAAkqk/KpFEJJR9vwE/s855/IMG_20130301_190022.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favourite share plate. Everything on this was perfect:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-pWLSYm4SfWE/UTD86ozsreI/AAAAAAAAkrQ/_3gQejEpjhE/s855/IMG_20130301_190351.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Biggest surprise for those who thought they didn&amp;rsquo;t like oysters:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-XsncxdffvyM/UTEAh1QgXpI/AAAAAAAAkrg/kBPB2HkXWO4/s855/IMG_20130301_192402.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The incredible sauce. I need that recipe!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-FWqsqV7S_zw/UTEAxAm3DuI/AAAAAAAAkr4/564m5NNn76M/s855/IMG_20130301_192450.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beautiful brill with patatas bravas (best pickled artichoke ever):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-WG8QAAbQOOM/UTECxwJtRqI/AAAAAAAAksI/UlLzS2dpnvs/s855/IMG_20130301_192718.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By 7.30pm I think we&amp;rsquo;d tried everything on the menu. And then we had the desserts. That thing with the granita was the nicest sweet I&amp;rsquo;ve had in years. Seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-ipFvK8jjL7s/UTEGiIUyaKI/AAAAAAAAks8/AnWw4qweVYA/s855/IMG_20130301_195005.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The others raved about this dessert too:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-_ltlpymRHMc/UTEGaqI8t7I/AAAAAAAAksw/-E1O-vkOq3Y/s855/IMG_20130301_194858.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rory told us that it was just a one-off experiment but can I implore Poacher&amp;rsquo;s to do this regularly? I know it had 5 chefs flat-out all night Friday so maybe once a month? And have it all night rather than the big-bang at 8pm? We haven&amp;rsquo;t eaten out much recently and it&amp;rsquo;s food like this that will get us out the door regularly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we first moved to Bandon, we were told that there were no good restaurants here because it was too close to Cork. So everyone went to Cork or Kinsale to eat. But Urru, Poacher&amp;rsquo;s and Chapel Steps have proven that was bullcrap and was just an excuse for mediocrity in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we get another couple of places of this quality in the town, it will become a serious foodie destination and rightly call itself the new gourmet capital of Cork.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doing something about bullying - Tuairisc</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.com/2013/01/29/doing-something-about-bullying-tuairisc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 09:07:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.com/2013/01/29/doing-something-about-bullying-tuairisc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Brian Greene contacted me last week about a new project he has just launched called &lt;a href=&#34;https://tuairisc.me/&#34;&gt;Tuairisc.me&lt;/a&gt;. Like many good ideas, it&amp;rsquo;s brilliantly simple. It&amp;rsquo;s an anti-bullying form for school web-sites that can be added with a single line of HTML to any site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tuairisc.me/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/tuairsc-logo-wide.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;tuairsc-logo-wide&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sent some questions/thoughts over to Brian and his responses convinced me that this thing has legs. But it will only work if as many people as possible know about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you are a parent, a teacher or even a student, let&amp;rsquo;s make this happen for your school. Get them to go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://tuairisc.me/&#34;&gt;Tuairisc.me&lt;/a&gt;, sign the school up for the FREE service and grab that one line of code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the school gets stuck adding the code, I&amp;rsquo;m sure many people, including me, would be glad to figure it out for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then get the message out. If your school uses SMS, send one. If it uses school-bag paper-slips, use that. Put posters in the school telling kids they can safely and securely report bullying via the school&amp;rsquo;s site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tuairisc.me/&#34;&gt;Tuairisc&lt;/a&gt; is another perfect example of a motivated tech person getting us from &amp;ldquo;someone should do something about this&amp;rdquo; to actually doing something about it. I hope we see many more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ballincollig&#39;s permanent Orienteering Trail points the way for all West Cork towns</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.com/2013/01/14/ballincolligs-permanent-orienteering-trail-points-the-way-for-all-west-cork-towns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2013 14:02:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.com/2013/01/14/ballincolligs-permanent-orienteering-trail-points-the-way-for-all-west-cork-towns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We recently did a short family outing to the forest in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.coillteoutdoors.ie/?id=53andrec_site=16&#34;&gt;Castlefreke&lt;/a&gt; just before the kids went back to school. Whilst the walk itself was fun and short enough to avoid the kids complaining too much, it brought up a ton of questions and ideas in my head, such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why is it so hard to find detailed information about walks/trails in West Cork and the rest of the country? The Irish Trails site is very poor indeed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why is Coillte sticking to unreadable-by-normal-people Ordnance Survey type &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.coillteoutdoors.ie/?id=53andrec_site=16&#34;&gt;maps in PDF format&lt;/a&gt; in 2013?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why doesn&amp;rsquo;t Coillte have iPhone and Android Apps for all forest activities?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t such an App be a perfect positive example of The Gathering in action?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t Google Streetview tours of the walks/trails/forests be an amazing resource?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why can&amp;rsquo;t I tell from online info if a walk/trail is buggy-friendly or small-child friendly?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why is signage in Irish forests so utterly useless?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why are we talking about selling off our forests rather than turning them into strong tourism revenue generators?
In the case of Castlefreke, rather than just complaining, I turned on a GPS tracker on my phone during the walk and uploaded much improved data to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openstreetmap.org/?lat=51.572699546813965andlon=-8.965208530426025andzoom=15&#34;&gt;Open Street Map&lt;/a&gt; afterwards. I&amp;rsquo;d do the same on Google Maps but they don&amp;rsquo;t have a Map Maker for Ireland yet. (Aside: Sign-up to be notified when it happens &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/google-mapmaker/wiki/MappingIE&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openstreetmap.org/?lat=51.572699546813965andlon=-8.965208530426025andzoom=15&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/rathbarry.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;rathbarry&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our next walk, my plan is to take a Contour GPS camera and video the whole thing with location info. So future walkers can see exactly what a trail is like rather than relying on vague text descriptions on web-sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it was a real joy for me to read &lt;a href=&#34;http://ballincollig.wordpress.com/2013/01/14/ballincollig-regional-park-orienteering-course-and-trails/&#34;&gt;Margaret Jordan&amp;rsquo;s blogpost&lt;/a&gt; this morning about the new permanent &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.corko.net/ballincollig_poc&#34;&gt;Orienteering Trail&lt;/a&gt; in Ballincollig Regional Park.  I did a bit of orienteering as a kid in the Scouts and absolutely loved it. It turned forest walks into an exciting adventure. It&amp;rsquo;s a sport that people of every age and ability can do. The one in Ballincollig sounds perfect for families.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you think about what&amp;rsquo;s involved, the cost to add this feature to any recreation space is very small. You could transform many barely used forests into hives of activity. But huge kudos to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cafechico.ie/&#34;&gt;Cafe Chico&lt;/a&gt; for sponsoring the one in Ballincollig.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that Bandon is now an &amp;ldquo;Active Travel town&amp;rdquo; and funding has supposedly been allocated for walking and cycling routes, wouldn&amp;rsquo;t orienteering be an ideal and inexpensive way of achieving the aims of that initiative? I know we don&amp;rsquo;t have many forests locally. I once tried to go for a walk in Duke&amp;rsquo;s wood and failed miserably after a few yards. I wonder if Castlebernard would be amenable to such a thing? Or Manch? Are there other places, not necessarily forests where this could be done safely?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the rest of West Cork there are plenty of areas where orienteering could slot right in. Imagine Lough Hyne or similar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thoughts? Problems? Suggestions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE 1: I just noticed from the Cork Orienteering Club site that Farran has &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.corko.net/maps&#34;&gt;a permanent course&lt;/a&gt; too. That&amp;rsquo;s two weekends sorted for us now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE 2 (20/01/2013): Today we had a go at the course in Ballincollig. We printed off 7 maps and the guide and got our warm clothes on. Overall we had good fun despite the usual kids complaints. But (big but!), you have to do it in wellies at this time of year. Most of the route is either off-path or on mud-filled paths. We did a short loop of the first 6 markers or so and were very mucky by the end. It&amp;rsquo;s not really suitable for people with buggies or very small children. Also if you want to split up into teams, there are a lot of rivers/streams/pools which means small kids must be accompanied by someone with sense. Highly recommended tho!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three full years a-running and my first Marathon</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.com/2013/01/02/three-full-years-a-running-and-my-first-marathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2013 10:26:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.com/2013/01/02/three-full-years-a-running-and-my-first-marathon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I thought I&amp;rsquo;d have a quick peek at my running stats this morning. Last year was pretty good and I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to start 2013 a whole 6 lbs lighter than I started 2012. Having said that, lots and lots of weight to be lost this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started &amp;ldquo;running&amp;rdquo; back in 2009. It was not an auspicious beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;28.43km
&lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;435.81km&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Timoleague: First 10km&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Half Marathons: Dingle, Galway
&lt;strong&gt;2011&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;394.39km&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;First road race in Vibram Five Fingers&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Half Marathons: Bandon, Amsterdam
&lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;849.41&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;10kms: Bandon&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Half Marathons: Cork, Clonakilty&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;First Marathon: Dublin
&lt;strong&gt;2013&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Second Marathon: Location TBD
I never did a blogpost on the Dublin Marathon. Must have been the mental scars :-) So here we go:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the Cork Half in June, I stated, as I always do, that I simply don&amp;rsquo;t have a marathon in me. But over July I thought more and more about it and finally, after a lot of egging on by my wife, signed-up to do the Dublin City Marathon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to follow the official training guide for a nice slow 5+ hour run. I was starting a month late but I figured the Cork Half training was an acceptable substitute. Overall training went very well even if the loop around Bandon does get a bit boring after the 3rd time in a day. Hopefully we&amp;rsquo;ll get a path all the way out to the railway path some time this decade. My schedule peaked at an 18 mile run which was very slow but gave me a huge boost in confidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day of the Marathon was quite chilly and we did the short walk up from the Mespil with windbreakers on. I was totally planking it. Despite lots of attempts at warm-up, I was very cold at the start, particularly my poor Vibram clad feet. And then we were off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to err on the side of total caution and went very slowly around Stephen&amp;rsquo;s Green and up O&amp;rsquo;Connell St. All felt good heading up to NCR and into the Phoenix Park. The Park is the longest and most boring part of the run. My right calf started to feel tight about half way through it. By the time I got to Chapelizod Gate, I was in serious trouble. The calf hurt more and more. The pain behind my knee getting worse with every step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally took a breather heading up to Kilmainham around mile 10 and walked up some hills. Walking was no better. And that was the rest of my Marathon. A mixture of walking, slow jogging and a tiny bit of running, barely able to extend my right leg at all. All my attempts to compensate ended up hurting shin muscles and then my left leg. Pure bloody torture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But here&amp;rsquo;s the amazing thing. At no point did I think I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t finish. Knowing all of the second half of the route inside-out was a huge help. I could just tick off sections in my head. Walkinstown, KCR, Terenure, Milltown, etc. That stubborn part of my brain simply decided that if it was going to take 8 hours, it was going to take 8 hours, even if I had to do it on all fours. I have &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Eat-Run-Ultramarathon-Greatness-ebook/dp/B005OCHOZS&#34;&gt;Scott Jurek&amp;rsquo;s book&lt;/a&gt; to thank for a lot of that mental attitude. If he can run 100 miles with his ankle held together with duct tape, I can do a jog around Dublin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The worst part was coming on to Merrion Road. The downhill on Nutley wasn&amp;rsquo;t bad and I jogged most of it but then I tried to walk on Merrion and saw that long long road stretching out in front of me and I wobbled mentally. So I stuck my headphones in for the first time and put on some Kermode and Mayo movie reviews to distract me. Then RunKeeper told me I was doing &amp;lt; 3 miles an hour. And I had more than 3 miles to go. Another hour of torture awaited me. So I bit the bullet and started jogging again. My speed was barely above walking. In fact many walkers passed me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But on I went. And I got to the bloody end. 6 hours and 32 minutes after I began.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the first thought as I crossed the finish line, apart from wanting to bawl crying, was &amp;ldquo;right, the next one is going to be a &lt;strong&gt;lot&lt;/strong&gt; faster&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Epilogue&lt;/em&gt; (In the best tradition of The Streets of San Francisco): Catherine had to help me get to a taxi and back to the hotel. I then peeled off the Vibrams and discovered I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a single blister. Not a one. Crippled but blister free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6 weeks later I did the Clonakilty Half. Still some aches and pains from Dublin but otherwise a grand run which proved that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t damaged anything irreparably.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we are planning our next one. We&amp;rsquo;re signed up for Berlin but that&amp;rsquo;s a long way away. London looks great but is pricey. Copenhagen looks fantastic in May but may be too hot (and pricey).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The training begins tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE 1: I decided to go for a short 3 mile run this evening. Very sore achilles but bloody hell, managed to do my &lt;a href=&#34;http://runkeeper.com/user/conoro/activity/139189568&#34;&gt;all-time fastest average speed over any distance&lt;/a&gt;. 2013 is off to a great start!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Alerting System from Cork County Council</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.com/2012/11/12/new-alerting-system-from-cork-county-council/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 14:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.com/2012/11/12/new-alerting-system-from-cork-county-council/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s great to see Cork CoCo finally putting an &lt;a href=&#34;http://mapalerts.corkcoco.ie/&#34;&gt;Alerts system&lt;/a&gt; in place. It&amp;rsquo;s very easy to use. You simply go to the relevant &lt;a href=&#34;http://mapalerts.corkcoco.ie/&#34;&gt;Map Alerts&lt;/a&gt; site and register there with your mobile/email/etc. You can also add your home and work locations for alerts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mapalerts.corkcoco.ie/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/logo.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;logo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now they are doing Alerts for Met Eireann Severe Weather Warnings in all of the County and for Flood Warnings in Clonakilty. I assume they&amp;rsquo;ll eventually integrate &lt;a href=&#34;http://bandonfloodwarning.ie/&#34;&gt;Bandon FEWS&lt;/a&gt; in too rather than running two separate systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other Alerts they will add in the future (presumably on the same opt-in basis) are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Road Closure and Scheduled Road Works&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Road Gritting and Salting Updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Road Incidents and Accidents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Water Service Disruptions and Boil Water Notices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Community and Miscellaneous Events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Major Emergencies
&lt;div&gt;You can see all the &lt;a href=&#34;http://mapalerts.corkcoco.ie/cork-alerts&#34;&gt;latest alerts&lt;/a&gt; here.&lt;/div&gt;
The system is powered by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mapalerter.com/&#34;&gt;Map Alerter&lt;/a&gt;, an Irish company based in Carlow and run by Brendan Cunningham. They already have several other CoCos using the system and I look forward to all counties signing up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MapAlerter &lt;a href=&#34;http://api.mapalerter.com/&#34;&gt;has an API&lt;/a&gt; and RSS feeds available and I&amp;rsquo;ll do a post here soon on how to use them for the Cork data. It&amp;rsquo;s a brilliant example of real #opendata being made available rather than being talked about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to assume some of the towns in the county are creating, or have created, iPhone/Android Apps for their town. Alerts would be a very useful addition to those.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well done to all involved.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bandon Coder Dojo on the move</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.com/2012/10/21/bandon-coder-dojo-on-the-move/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 10:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.com/2012/10/21/bandon-coder-dojo-on-the-move/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://zen.coderdojo.com/dojo/144&#34;&gt;Bandon Coder Dojo&lt;/a&gt; kicked off this year and they have just made the move to St Brogans school at the top of the town. It&amp;rsquo;s on every Tuesday from 6:30pm to 8pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are currently focused on &lt;a href=&#34;http://scratch.mit.edu/&#34;&gt;Scratch&lt;/a&gt;, HTML and JavaScript. If you have any skills in those areas, they would really appreciate more mentors taking part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our eldest has just started using Scratch and is finding it good fun. Here&amp;rsquo;s a screenshot:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Scratch-tutorials5.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://conoroneill.com.s3.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Scratch-tutorials5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;Scratch tutorials5&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You currently need to have a laptop to take part in Coder Dojo. I know this excludes a lot of people but &lt;a href=&#34;http://coderdojo.com/2012/09/18/camara-laptops/&#34;&gt;Camara Ireland&lt;/a&gt; has stepped in to help there. You can get reconditioned laptops from them via the Coder Dojo movement for between €114 and €125, which is a great price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also wonder if there is any possibility for school PCs to be used during the Coder Dojos too? Or perhaps, over time, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raspberrypi.org/faqs&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pis&lt;/a&gt; which people can bring and hook up to the monitors there? This would maximise the number of people who can get involved with Coder Dojo, no matter what their financial situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that parents must accompany children for the entire session. If you have any questions about it at all, contact bandoncoderdojo@gmail.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finally, together at last, Vibram Five Fingers and Sugru</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.com/2012/08/31/finally-together-at-last-vibram-five-fingers-and-sugru/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 15:15:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.com/2012/08/31/finally-together-at-last-vibram-five-fingers-and-sugru/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My two favourite products working together to make me run like the wind (&lt;em&gt;cough&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-R3yoBsW98yY/UECt2rNo1MI/AAAAAAAAiv4/ZHwOOOD9bDA/s957/IMG_20120831_131546.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;VFFs and Sugru&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I switched from running in Bikilas to these TrekSports, I started getting a sore spot just behind the ball of my left foot. It appears to be due to a seam on the VFFs rubbing me. Using a temporary pad worked during the week so now I&amp;rsquo;m hoping this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sugru.com&#34;&gt;Sugru&lt;/a&gt; fix will be permanent. I have to run 5 miles tonight so that should prove it one way or another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>