<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conor&#39;s Bandon Blog</title>
    <link>https://conoroneill.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Conor&#39;s Bandon Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 06:42:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://conoroneill.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Flight EI123 and the death of the Aer Lingus brand</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2018/10/15/flight-ei123-and-the-death-of-the-aer-lingus-brand/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 06:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2018/10/15/flight-ei123-and-the-death-of-the-aer-lingus-brand/</guid>
      <description>Buckle up, this is going to be the rantiest rant I&amp;rsquo;ve written in years. It&amp;rsquo;s mostly about getting it off my chest as, based on our experiences over October 5th and 6th, it will have zero effect on the dire state of Aer Lingus.
Let&amp;rsquo;s do the timeline first and then dive into the death of once-well-regarded brand.
An early start but lots of excitement My wife, 5 kids and I woke at 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alex Honnold free solo 360 video - Mind-blowing in Google Cardboard</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2018/09/29/alex-honnold-free-solo-360-video-mind-blowing-in-google-cardboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 22:50:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2018/09/29/alex-honnold-free-solo-360-video-mind-blowing-in-google-cardboard/</guid>
      <description>If you don&amp;rsquo;t have a Google Cardboard, you can still get some sense of the scale of what Alex Honnold achieved this year when he free soloed El Capitan in Yosemite if you use the 3D controls in YouTube.
Free Soloing is climbing without any equipment or safety ropes. What Alex did is one of the greatest sporting achievements by a human ever.
   &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;
I&amp;rsquo;ve no massive interest in climbing but after watching the Valley Uprising documentary last night (available to buy or watch or Netflix), I have a whole new appreciation for the mindset and philosophy of people like Honnold and John Bachar before him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mario Fraioli on Eliud Kipchoge&#39;s performance in Berlin</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2018/09/18/mario-fraioli-on-eliud-kipchoges-performance-in-berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 15:20:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2018/09/18/mario-fraioli-on-eliud-kipchoges-performance-in-berlin/</guid>
      <description>Mario nailed it, as always, in his weekly newsletter. You should subscribe.
&amp;ldquo;I understand the disbelief and the need to explain what many deemed impossible without some kind of assistance. But what if, at the end of the day, as Alex Hutchinson wrote for Outside, it was all Kipchoge? What if we were simply watching the greatest distance runner of all-time painting his masterpiece in real-time? What if we were witnessing the greatest feat of human endurance in history?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From NYC to Kerry, a wrap-up of my races over the past year</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2018/09/10/from-nyc-to-kerry-a-wrap-up-of-my-races-over-the-past-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 07:50:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2018/09/10/from-nyc-to-kerry-a-wrap-up-of-my-races-over-the-past-year/</guid>
      <description>Apart from a couple like the Liverpool to Manchester 50 miler, I haven&amp;rsquo;t been keeping up on my mini race reports over the past year. Hopefully you&amp;rsquo;ll find them useful if you&amp;rsquo;re planning for next year. I&amp;rsquo;ll keep them short and sweet.
New York City Marathon I&amp;rsquo;m not sure whey I never did a full race report on this because it was an incredible experience. It overtook London as the marathon that emotionally impacted me the most.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This week&#39;s most motivational videos</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2018/09/07/this-weeks-most-motivational-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 07:20:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2018/09/07/this-weeks-most-motivational-videos/</guid>
      <description>Love them or hate them as a company, but wow Nike knows how to make amazing ads. It&amp;rsquo;d almost make me buy a pair of Epic Reacts to balance the redneck backlash in the US.
  And these selfless people just blow my mind:
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Kerry Ultra 50K - Go on, sign-up for 2019</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2018/09/02/the-kerry-ultra-50k-go-on-sign-up-for-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 18:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2018/09/02/the-kerry-ultra-50k-go-on-sign-up-for-2019/</guid>
      <description>The Kerry Ultra 50K was somehow not on my radar but luckily my wife spotted it recently. We decided to do it barely a week beforehand.
Unlike a lot of ultras over in the UK, this one was all on-road and mostly self-supported. There was a small table every 10K with water and Redbull only.
We went down to Tralee the night before to make the race briefing. Brian O&amp;rsquo;Shea went into huge detail on both the 50K and 100K which weirdly made me more stressed than if I&amp;rsquo;d known nothing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Damn that was an exciting UTMB. Well done iRunFar on the coverage!</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2018/09/02/damn-that-was-an-exciting-utmb.-well-done-irunfar-on-the-coverage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 17:40:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2018/09/02/damn-that-was-an-exciting-utmb.-well-done-irunfar-on-the-coverage/</guid>
      <description>As always, amazing coverage from the iRunFar crew who deserve all your Patreon support. I was thrilled to get some of their stickers in the post this week. I also wear my iRunFar t-shirt as often as possible.
Their interview with women&amp;rsquo;s winner Francesca Canepa:
  .
and men&amp;rsquo;s winner Xavier Thévenard:
  .
I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to spend time near Chamonix next year to finally check out those amazing trails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I finally watched Breaking Glass 38 years later</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2018/08/31/i-finally-watched-breaking-glass-38-years-later/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 23:06:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2018/08/31/i-finally-watched-breaking-glass-38-years-later/</guid>
      <description>As a 12 year old kid, the ads for Breaking Glass looked amazing. Somehow I never watched it until tonight.
It hasn&amp;rsquo;t aged well. From the general cheapness to the ropey writing, acting and directing, it should be awful. But it isn&amp;rsquo;t, it&amp;rsquo;s lovely. Hazel O&amp;rsquo;Connor, Hazel&amp;rsquo;s songs and Hazel&amp;rsquo;s voice remain utterly unique.
The movie is also a reminder that no matter how bad things are now, they aren&amp;rsquo;t half as bad as the late 70s and early 80s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excitement building over UTMB</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2018/08/17/excitement-building-over-utmb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 07:36:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2018/08/17/excitement-building-over-utmb/</guid>
      <description>The organisers of UTMB (Ultra Trail du Mont Blanc) do an amazing job of the coverage every year. Head over to their site at 5pm Irish on Friday Aug 31st for live footage at the race start. In the meantime here&amp;rsquo;s a lovely video by Salomon of brilliant ultra runner Ryan Sandes and his buddies doing a tour of Mont Blanc.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test of my new email-to-hugo blogging tool</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2018/08/13/test-of-my-new-email-to-hugo-blogging-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 11:06:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2018/08/13/test-of-my-new-email-to-hugo-blogging-tool/</guid>
      <description>I have created a simple new tool which enables me to send blog
content via email. The emails are converted to Markdown files and then
uploaded to a Hugo source repo on GitHub, along with any inline images.
CircleCI then automatically rebuilds and redeploys my blog to S3.
I’ll post full details and source code over the next few days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking away from Facebook after 11 years.</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2018/08/10/walking-away-from-facebook-after-11-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2018/08/10/walking-away-from-facebook-after-11-years/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to write about giving up on Twitter since last November. I think I&amp;rsquo;ll now wait until I&amp;rsquo;ve been off for 12 months.
I kept threatening to walk on Facebook too. I&amp;rsquo;d like to thank Facebook for killing the List Feed feature today so they made the decision for me. I&amp;rsquo;m done.
My first two posts on Facebook were in 2006 and 2007. I was complaining about it even then!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Castlefreke is exactly why all State lands must be immediately be removed from the hands of logging company Coillte</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2018/06/09/castlefreke-remove-state-lands-from-coillte/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2018/06/09/castlefreke-remove-state-lands-from-coillte/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s get straight to the point. Coillte is a logging company with a commercial mandate. Having it in charge of 440,000 hectares of state lands is so idiotically Irish, you don&amp;rsquo;t know whether to laugh or cry. All state lands should be transferred to a hugely expanded and reformulated National Parks and Wildlife Service immediately. The NPWS can then licence Coillte to plant and harvest trees in a strictly controlled fashion on a limited subset of those lands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Liverpool to Manchester - Conor does his 50 (miles) before 50 (years)</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2018/04/08/from-liverpool-to-manchester-conor-does-50-before-50/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 09:49:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2018/04/08/from-liverpool-to-manchester-conor-does-50-before-50/</guid>
      <description>Last March I decided I wanted to run a 50 mile race before I hit the big five oh in May of this year. On Monday, in spite of freezing rain, hail, sleet and snow, I somehow managed it and I can&amp;rsquo;t stop randomly grinning.
As always, have no fear, this won&amp;rsquo;t be a mile-by-mile race report. I&amp;rsquo;d fall asleep writing it :-) Speaking of which, one of my ultra-running top tips is &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t listen to the audiobook of &amp;lsquo;Why We Sleep&amp;rsquo; on miles 30-40 of a 50 miler if you want to avoid getting verrrrry verrrry sleepy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m more excited about Eoin Keith doing the Barkley Marathons than I am about my first 50 miler</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2018/03/17/eoin-keith-barkley-marathons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 09:49:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2018/03/17/eoin-keith-barkley-marathons/</guid>
      <description>Like many people I&amp;rsquo;ve been enthralled by Eoin Keith&amp;rsquo;s Ultra running exploits since I first discovered this crazy sport. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s his Spine Race wins in crazy weather or his FKT from Mizen to Malin, he makes you want to push yourself and try things.
My wife and I are doing the Liverpool to Manchester 50 Mile Ultra very soon (oh god it really is very very soon) and we flip-flop between terror and huge excitement over the adventure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The fatally flawed Salomon Sense Pro Max</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2018/03/12/the-fatally-flawed-salomon-sense-pro-max/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 06:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2018/03/12/the-fatally-flawed-salomon-sense-pro-max/</guid>
      <description>I read some reviews of the Sense Pro Max last year and they looked like a good pair of mixed surface running shoes. However they came with the usual Salomon price tag and I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a specific need for them.
Fast-forward to January this year and I started getting worried about the footwear I was going to use in my first 50 Miler, the Liverpool to Manchester Ultra. Then I spotted that the Salomons were half price on Wiggle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 - The year of running 1000 miles</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2017/12/30/2017-the-year-of-running-1000-miles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2017/12/30/2017-the-year-of-running-1000-miles/</guid>
      <description>2017 was probably the year I stopped feeling odd when calling myself a runner. I achieved a bunch of new things in running, including my first 50k, and managed to do just over 1000 miles for the year.
Start running now If you are thinking of taking up running in the new year, go for it. No excuses. Forget about &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll wait until I&amp;rsquo;ve lost some weight&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;when the weather improves&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;my knee is a bit twingey&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A round-up of Conor&#39;s recent races. Lots to recommend!</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2017/10/02/a-round-up-of-conors-recent-races-lots-to-recommend/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 19:50:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2017/10/02/a-round-up-of-conors-recent-races-lots-to-recommend/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been having fun mixing up the length and style of the races we&amp;rsquo;ve run this Summer and Autumn. Whilst my speed remains atrocious, I find that my recovery time is getting shorter and shorter, which must be a sign of something. So here goes, June to September:
Cork City Marathon What can I say? It broke me again. I started so well - faster than last year and feeling strong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dear headphone manufacturers - Big opportunity to own the marathon market</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2017/09/06/headphone-companies-big-opportunity-to-own-the-marathon-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 06:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2017/09/06/headphone-companies-big-opportunity-to-own-the-marathon-market/</guid>
      <description>I really wonder about headphone manufacturers and their testing. I own everything from no-name €10 Chinese wired earbuds to €100+ Jaybird X3s and every single one of them is problematic for running.
In the US alone, over 550,000 people ran a marathon in 2016. Scale that globally (with a 13% growth rate) and that&amp;rsquo;s a substantial, defined, receptive, target market.
My goto pair for the past 2 years are SMS In-Ear Wired Sport earbuds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of The Trail Runner&#39;s Companion by Sarah Lavender Smith</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2017/08/30/review-of-the-trail-runners-companion-by-sarah-lavender-smith/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 18:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2017/08/30/review-of-the-trail-runners-companion-by-sarah-lavender-smith/</guid>
      <description>I wrote about my first 50k a few weeks back. I still smile every time I think about it. I&amp;rsquo;m already signed up for a 40 miler in the Glen of Aherlow in September (3 loops, so I have a get-out-of-jail) and I&amp;rsquo;m trying to decide what my first 50 miler will be. Suffice to say, I&amp;rsquo;m really getting into this whole trail running thing. And one of the main reasons for that is the brilliant work done by YouTubers, Instagrammers and Podcasters in this area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Chiltern Challenge 50k - Conor&#39;s First Ultra Marathon</title>
      <link>https://conoroneill.com/2017/07/23/the-chiltern-challenge-50k-conors-first-ultra-marathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2017 20:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conoroneill.com/2017/07/23/the-chiltern-challenge-50k-conors-first-ultra-marathon/</guid>
      <description>I made this comment on Twitter last week:
Any chance we can narrow &amp;quot;inspirational&amp;quot; to mean &amp;quot;inspired me to action&amp;quot; instead of &amp;quot;isn&amp;#39;t that a nice story&amp;quot;?
&amp;mdash; Conor O&amp;#39;Neill (@conoro) July 19, 2017 
It was partially driven by the silly overuse of &amp;ldquo;inspirational&amp;rdquo; but also by the fact that I was inspired to run 50km last weekend by all of the amazing Ultrarunners in the US and Europe and the stories they tell via YouTube, Vimeo, Blogs, Twitter, Instagram, magazines and books.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>